Okay. Hi everyone.
好的。嗨，大家好。
Let's get started [NOISE] Okay.
让我们开始吧[NOISE]好的。
So, so for today's lecture,
那么，今天的讲座，
what we're gonna do is look at the topic of having Tree Recursive Neural Networks.
我们要做的是查看树递归神经网络的主题。
I mean, this is actually, uh,
我的意思是，这实际上是，呃，
a topic which I feel especially fond of and attached to,
一个我特别喜欢和附属的话题，
because actually when we started doing deep learning for NLP here at Stanford in 2010,
因为实际上当我们在2010年开始在斯坦福大学深入学习NLP时，
really for the sort of period from 2010 to 2015,
真的是从2010年到2015年的那段时间，
the dominant set of ideas that we were working on was this topic of how you
我们正在研究的主要观点是你如何这个主题
could build a recur- recursive tree structure into neural networks.
可以在神经网络中构建一个递归树结构。
So in a way, it's kind of funny that I'm only getting to it now.
所以在某种程度上，我现在只能接受它，这很有趣。
I mean, there are sort of reasons for that,
我的意思是，有这样的原因，
but I think there are a bunch of interesting ideas
但我认为有很多有趣的想法
here which relate closely to linguistic structure,
这里与语言结构密切相关，
and so it's good stuff to have seen.
所以看到它是件好事。
But in practice, um,
但在实践中，嗯，
these ideas have proven kind of hard to scale
这些想法已被证明难以扩展
and not necessarily to work better in practice than
并不一定在实践中更好地工作
the kind of things that we've spent more time on
我们花了更多时间的东西
meaning things like looking at LSTMs and looking at transformers,
意思是看LSTM和看变形金刚，
and things like that.
和那样的事情。
And so that's kinda why we sort of shunted them towards the end of the curriculum.
所以这就是为什么我们会在课程结束时将它们分开。
But I want to sort of say something about the motivations,
但我想谈谈动机，
and the ways you can build tree structures,
以及构建树结构的方法，
and neural networks, and look at some of the possibilities,
和神经网络，并看看一些可能性，
um, we explored um,
嗯，我们探究过你，
in during this class.
在这堂课上。
Um, another fact about this class is actually this is the last class I'm going to give.
嗯，关于这堂课的另一个事实实际上这是我要给的最后一堂课。
Um, so two more classes next week.
嗯，下周还有两节课。
Don't forget about next week, um,
别忘了下周，嗯，
CS224N classes, um,
CS224N课程，嗯，
but on Tuesday, um,
但是周二，嗯，
we've gotten the final invited speaker, ,
我们得到了最后邀请的演讲者，
who's a great speaker and has tons of interesting stuff
谁是一个伟大的演讲者，有很多有趣的东西
to say about fairness and ethics in NLP and AI.
在NLP和AI中谈论公平和道德。
And then for the final lecture,
然后进行最后的讲座，
one of my- another of my PhD students  is
我的另一位博士生是
gonna give that and talk about some of the recent,
要给出并谈谈最近的一些，
what's been happening in deep learning in 2018, '19,
在2018年的深度学习中发生了什么，'19，
of some of the sort of recent developments in NLP and deep learning. Um,
NLP和深度学习的一些近期发展。嗯，
so, um, let's- I'll say my farewells at the end of this one.
所以，嗯，让我们在这一节结束时告别我的告别。
Um, so hopefully, everyone has submitted, um,
嗯，希望每个人都提交了，嗯，
their, um, milestone for their final project.
他们的，最后项目的里程碑。
If you haven't, you should really begin your milestone in- um,
如果你还没有，你应该真正开始你的里程碑，
you know, it's inevitable that somewhere around here,
你知道吗，这里的某个地方不可避免
there start to be problems that people have the situation that nothing works,
人们开始出现无事无益的问题，
and everything is too slow, and you panic.
一切都太慢了，你恐慌。
Um, and, um, this happens.
嗯，而且，嗯，这发生了。
Um, I wish you luck, of course.
嗯，我祝你好运，当然。
I mean, what can you do about it?
我的意思是，你能做些什么呢？
I mean, it can be really hard when you have things that don't work as to work out,
我的意思是，如果你的东西不起作用，那真的很难，
why they don't work,
为什么他们不工作，
and how to fix them.
以及如何解决它们。
I mean, I think often the best thing to do is really to go back to something
我的意思是，我认为通常最好的办法就是回归某些事情
simple that you can get working and to work forward from there again.
很简单，你可以继续工作，并再次从那里前进。
It also really helps to have really small data sets.
拥有非常小的数据集也很有帮助。
I really recommend the strategy of sort of having a 10-item,
我真的推荐一种有10个项目的策略，
or 20-item data set and checking that your model works perfectly,
或20项数据集并检查您的模型是否完美，
over-trains to 100 percent accuracy on that kind of data
对这类数据进行过度训练，达到100％的准确率
set saves you huge amounts of time,
套装可以节省大量的时间，
and it's sort of after you've gotten something simple working on a small amount of data,
在你完成一些简单的小数据工作之后，
that's the right time to sort of then,
那时候是正确的时间，
um, expand forward again.
嗯，再次向前扩展。
Um, you should definitely always make sure that
嗯，你一定要确保这一点
you can completely overfit on your training data set.
你可以完全过度训练你的训练数据集。
That's sort of, um,
那是那种，嗯，
not quite a proof,
不完全证明，
but it's at least a first good requirement for your model being implemented properly.
但这至少是你的模型正确实施的第一个好要求。
Um, you, you know part of the trick of being
嗯，你，你知道存在的一部分技巧
a successful deep learning researcher is actually
实际上，一个成功的深度学习研究员
managing to get things done and not wasting a ton of time.
设法完成任务而不是浪费大量时间。
And so it definitely always helps just to be, you know,
所以，你知道，这总是有帮助的。
plotting as you go along your training and
在你的训练和你的训练中密谋
dev errors so that you can sort of tell if things are working,
开发错误，以便您可以判断事情是否正常，
or if things aren't working,
或者如果事情不起作用，
and you should abandon and start again with a new experiment,
你应该放弃并重新开始一个新的实验，
tha- that just things like that save you hours and get you, uh, more done.
那么这样的事情可以节省你的时间并让你，呃，做得更多。
And so then once things are working,
一旦事情奏效，那么
there's sort of a whole bunch of things to make it work better.
有很多东西可以让它更好地运作。
There's regularization with L2 and Dropout,
有L2和Dropout的正规化，
there's time to do hyperparameter search,
有时间进行超参数搜索，
um, and, you know,
嗯，你知道，
often doing these things and make quite a lot of difference to what
经常做这些事情，并做出很大的改变
your final results are and so it's good to have time to do those things.
你的最终结果是，所以有时间做这些事情是件好事。
But clearly, you want to get things, um,
但显然，你想得到的东西，嗯，
working first before you go on to that, um,
在你继续之前先做好工作，嗯，
and sort of really encourage people to still
并且真的鼓励人们继续
stop by in office hours if you've got any problems,
如果你有任何问题，请在办公时间停下来，
and we'll try our best to help out here within
我们会尽力在这里提供帮助
the limitations of what we can do from just being hit cold with problems.
我们可以做些什么来解决问题。
Okay, um, yeah.
好的，恩，是的
So, I wanted to sort of just say some general remarks about, um,
所以，我想说一些关于的一般性评论，嗯，
language and theories of language,
语言和语言理论，
um, that, in the context that motivate these tree recursive networks.
嗯，在激励这些树递归网络的环境中。
Um, so this is an art installation at Carnegie Mellon University.
嗯，这是卡内基梅隆大学的艺术装置。
And as an NLP person,
作为一个NLP人，
I really love this art installation.
我真的很喜欢这个艺术装置。
Um, so we need better art installations around the Stanford School of Engineering.
嗯，所以我们需要在斯坦福工程学院附近进行更好的艺术装置。
Um, so this is the bag-of-words art Installation.
嗯，所以这就是文字艺术装置。
There's the bag with a lot of words in it.
包里面有很多单词。
And you see down here,
你在这里看到，
there were the stop words, the the, and the us,
有停止的话，the和我们，
that had fallen out of the bag,
从包里掉了出来，
and are represented on the ground as the stop words.
并在地面上作为停止词表示。
Beautiful artwork, right? So, um,
美丽的艺术品，对吗？那么，嗯，
one of the interesting things that has been found about NLP models of language,
关于NLP语言模型的一个有趣的事情，
and I think this is even more true in
我认为这更加真实
the deep learning world than it used to be previously is,
比以前更深刻的学习世界是，
boy, you can do a lot with bag-of-words models, right?
男孩，你可以用词袋模型做很多事，对吧？
That you can just often get a lot of power by saying,
通过说，你可以经常获得很多权力，
well, let's get our neural word vectors,
好吧，让我们得到我们的神经词向量，
we're gonna average them or max pool them,
我们要平均他们或最大值他们，
or something like this,
或类似的东西，
and do nothing more,
而且什么都不做，
and that gives me a pretty good sentence representation or
这给了我一个很好的句子代表或
document representation that I could use in a classifier or something.
我可以在分类器或其他东西中使用的文档表示。
And sometimes, you can do not much more than that and get even better.
有时，你可以做的不仅仅是那些，而是变得更好。
So people have done things like deep averaging networks where you're taking
因此，人们已经做了诸如深度平均网络之类的事情
the output of a bag-of-words model and sort of
一个袋子模型和类型的输出
feeding it through a couple more layers and improving things.
通过更多层次提供它并改善事物。
So that is in complete distinction to
所以这是完全不同的
what's been dominant in linguistics of looking at language structure.
在语言学中看待语言结构的主导因素是什么。
That typically in linguistics the emphasis has been on identifying kind of
通常在语言学中，重点是识别类型
huge amounts of structure of linguistic utterances through very complex formalisms.
通过非常复杂的形式主义，大量的语言表达结构。
I guess this is sort of a bit of a picture of a Chomsky minimalism syntactic tree,
我想这有点像乔姆斯基极简主义句法树的图片，
and the one up at the top is a bit of a picture of head-driven phrase structure grammar.
而顶部的一个是头部驱动的短语结构语法的图片。
Which was a theory that was predominantly, um,
这主要是一种理论，嗯，
developed at Stanford in the '90s.
在上世纪90年代在斯坦福大学发展起来。
Um, but sort of very complex data structures and
嗯，但有点非常复杂的数据结构和
articulated structures used to describe linguistics.
用于描述语言学的铰接结构。
And there's a huge gap between these two things.
这两件事之间存在巨大差距。
And you might think that, you know, surely,
你可能会认为，当然，
there's some good points in the middle where we have a certain amount of structure,
在我们有一定数量的结构的中间有一些好点，
and that's going to help us do what we want.
这将帮助我们做我们想做的事。
And so in particular, um,
尤其如此，嗯，
that if we're wanting to semantically interpret language,
如果我们想要语义解释语言，
it seems like we don't just want to have word vectors,
看起来我们不只是想拥有单词向量，
we want to have meanings of bigger phrases.
我们希望有更大的短语的含义。
So here's the snowboarders leaping over a mogul,
所以这里的挡雪板跳过一个大人物，
and a person on a snowboard jumps into the air.
一个人在滑雪板上跳到空中。
And what we'd like to be able to say is that the snowboarder
我们想要说的是滑雪板
means basically the same thing as a person on the snowboard.
与滑雪板上的人基本相同。
So we wanted to have these chunks of
所以我们想拥有这些块
language which in linguistics will be constituent  phrases,
语言学中将成为组成短语的语言，
and say that they have a meaning,
并说他们有意义，
and we'd like to be able to compare their meaning.
我们希望能够比较它们的含义。
Now, we've looked at at least one tool that allows us to have chunks of language, right?
现在，我们已经研究了至少一种允许我们拥有大量语言的工具，对吗？
Because we looked at convolutional neural networks where you could take
因为我们查看了你可以采取的卷积神经网络
three words and make a representation of the convolutional neural network,
三个单词并表示卷积神经网络，
but the fundamental difference is that in
但根本区别在于
human languages you have these chunks that have meaning,
人类语言你有这些有意义的块，
that are of different sizes.
有不同的大小。
So we'd like to say the snowboarder
所以我们想说滑雪板
is pretty much semantically equivalent to a person on the snowboard,
在语义上相当于滑雪板上的人，
but the top one is two words long,
但最重要的是两个字长，
and the bottom one is five words long.
最下面一个是五个字。
And so if we're gonna be able to do that, um,
所以，如果我们能够做到这一点，嗯，
we somehow wanted to have these sort of constituent chunks and be
我们不知何故想要拥有这些组成块
able to work with and represent them in neural networks.
能够在神经网络中使用并表示它们。
And that's sort of, um,
那是那种，嗯，
the central idea of what
什么是中心思想
motivated some of the sort of tree structured neural networks that I'm about to show you.
激发了一些我即将向你展示的树形结构神经网络。
There's another related thing that you might wanna think about is, you know,
您可能想要考虑的另一个相关的事情是，你知道，
a person on a snowboard,
一个人在滑雪板上，
how do human beings manage to understand what that means?
人类如何理解这意味着什么？
And then a person on a snowboard jumps into the air,
然后一个人在滑雪板上跳到空中，
how does people manage to understand what that means?
人们如何理解这意味着什么？
And it sort of seems like the only possible answer to
它似乎是唯一可能的答案
this is what's normally referred to as the principle of compositionality.
这通常被称为组合原则。
That people know the word person,
人们都知道这个词，
they know the word on,
他们知道这个词，
they know the word snowboard, therefore,
他们知道滑雪板这个词，因此，
they can work out what on a snowboard means, um,
他们可以在滑雪板上找出什么意思，嗯，
and they can work out what person on a snowboard means by knowing
他们可以通过了解来确定滑雪板上的人是什么意思
the meanings of components and putting them together into bigger pieces.
组件的含义并将它们组合成更大的部件。
There's a f- there's a famous,
有一个f-有一个着名的，
um, applied mathematician statistician, um,
嗯，应用数学家统计学家，嗯，
at Brown University, Stu Geman, and I guess the way he summarized this is,
在布朗大学，Stu Geman，我猜他总结的方式是，
either the principle of compositionality is true, or God exists.
组合原则是真的，还是上帝存在的。
Um, for [LAUGHTER] which he was, um,
嗯，对于[笑声]他是谁，嗯，
well you can take that as- as you want but, you know,
那么你可以随心所欲，但是，你知道，
um, I think what he meant was well, you know,
嗯，我想他的意思很好，你知道，
you can just make these infinite number of
你可以做出这些无数的
infinitely long sentences and human beings understand them,
无限长的句子和人类理解它们，
that it just has to be that people can know about
它只是人们可以知道的
words and ways to combine meanings and-and make bigger meanings because,
将意义和意义结合起来的意义和方法，因为，
you know, how else could it possibly work that people could understand sentences.
你知道吗，人们怎么能理解句子。
And so we want to be able to do that.
所以我们希望能够做到这一点。
We want to be able to work out semantic compositions of smaller elements,
我们希望能够计算出较小元素的语义成分，
to work out the meanings of bigger pieces.
弄清楚更大的作品的意义。
And that this obviously isn't only a linguistic thing,
这显然不仅仅是一种语言学的东西，
compositionality, um, appears in other places as well, right.
组合性，嗯，也出现在其他地方，对吧。
So, um, if you want to understand how some piece of machinery works,
所以，嗯，如果你想了解某些机器是如何工作的，
what you kind of wanna know is it has different sub-components.
你有点想知道的是它有不同的子组件。
And if you can understand how
如果你能理解如何
the different sub-components work and how they're fitted together,
不同的子组件工作以及它们如何组合在一起，
um, then you might have some understanding of how the whole scene works.
嗯，那么你可能对整个场景的运作方式有所了解。
Um, and, um, compositionality seems to be wor- at work in vision as well.
嗯，而且，嗯，组合性似乎也是在视觉上的工作。
So here is a scene and again it seems like this scene has parts.
所以这是一个场景，看起来这个场景似乎有部分。
So there are little parts that go together, right.
所以很少有部分组合在一起，对吧。
So there are people that go together into a crowd of people,
所以有些人聚集在一群人中，
and there's a roof and a second floor and another bit of roof.
还有一个屋顶和一个二楼以及另一个屋顶。
and a first floor that go together into a picture of this church.
和一楼一起拍摄这座教堂的照片。
And so this is also kind of a compositional scene in which pieces go together.
因此，这也是一种组合场景，其中各个部分组合在一起。
So it sort of seems like certainly for language understanding,
所以对于语言理解来说，这似乎是肯定的，
and then really for a lot of the other things that we use for intelligence,
然后真的用于我们用于智能的很多其他事情，
that we somehow need to be able to understand
我们不知何故需要能够理解
bigger things from knowing about smaller parts.
了解较小部件的更大事情。
Um, yeah, so computational- so the most- I mentioned this earlier,
嗯，是的，所以计算 - 所以最多 - 我之前提到的，
sometime the most famous, um,
有时最有名的，嗯，
linguist is Noam Chomsky at MIT and,
语言学家是麻省理工学院的Noam Chomsky，
um, you know, really computational linguists,
嗯，你知道，真正的计算语言学家，
a lot of the time haven't been that friendly to, um,
很多时候都没那么友好，嗯，
linguistics linguists and in particular some of Noam Chomsky's, um,
语言学语言学家，尤其是诺姆乔姆斯基的一些语言学家，嗯，
theories of language because really he's never been
语言理论因为他从未去过
sympathetic to the idea of machine learning.
同情机器学习的想法。
Or in general does some of the empirical ability to learn from data.
或者一般来说做一些从数据中学习的经验能力。
He's sort of always been, um,
他总是这样，嗯，
[NOISE] wanting to refuse to that exists.
[NOISE]想要拒绝存在。
But, um, if we nevertheless look for a little bit of,
但是，嗯，如果我们仍然寻找一点，
um, insight on that.
嗯，对此的见解。
Um, you know, this is a recent paper of Chomsky's with authors and that they're sort
嗯，你知道，这是乔姆斯基最近发表的一篇有关作者的论文，他们很有兴趣
of trying to give a version of what is unique about human language.
试图给出一个人类语言独特的版本。
And essentially what they, um,
基本上他们是什么，嗯，
zero in on is that well,
归零就是这样，
if you're sort of looking at, you know,
如果你有点看，你知道，
humans versus other fairly intelligent creatures.
人类与其他相当聪明的生物。
They suggest that the defining difference of human beings, um,
他们认为人类的决定性差异，嗯，
is that they have this ability to model recursion.
是他们有这种模拟递归的能力。
And so the- this paper argues that the- the singular distinction that allowed
因此 - 本文认为 - 允许的单一区别
language to develop in human beings was that we
人类发展的语言就是我们
could put together smaller parts to make bigger things,
可以把较小的部分放在一起制作更大的东西，
in a recursive process and that that was the sort of defining new ability.
在递归过程中，这就是定义新能力的那种。
Um, not sure I- not sure I believe that or not,
嗯，不确定我 - 不确定我是否相信，
um, [LAUGHTER] you can decide what you think.
嗯，[大笑]你可以决定你的想法。
But what I think, um,
但我的想法是，嗯，
is certainly the case is that- it's just incontrovertible that
当然是这样的 - 这是无可争议的
the structure of human language sentences have these pieces,
人类语言句子的结构有这些部分，
um, constituents that then form together hierarchically or
嗯，成分，然后分层次地或
recursively into bigger pieces as you go up in the tree.
当你走进树里时，递归地变成更大的碎片。
And in particular you get this recursion where you get a little noun phrase meat,
特别是你得到这个递归，你得到一个小名词短语肉，
which then appears in a bigger noun phrase like spaghetti with meat.
然后出现在一个更大的名词短语中，如肉意大利面。
And you can repeat that several times,
你可以重复几次，
giving you a recursive structure.
给你一个递归结构。
And I have an example of that in blue up at the top.
我有一个例子，在蓝色的顶部。
So the person standing next to the man from
所以那个站在男人旁边的人
the company that purchased the firm that you used to work at,
购买了您曾经工作过的公司的公司，
um, that whole thing is a big noun phrase.
嗯，整件事是一个大名词短语。
Um, but inside that there's a noun phrase,
嗯，但里面有一个名词短语，
the man from the company that purchased the firm that you used to work at,
购买了您曾经工作过的公司的公司的人，
which is another big noun phrase.
这是另一个大名词短语。
And well inside that, um,
嗯，嗯，
there are smaller noun phrases like,
还有较小的名词短语，
the company that purchased the firm you used to work at.
购买你曾经工作过的公司的公司。
But, you know, it's still got inside that noun phrases like,
但是，你知道，它仍然在里面，名词短语，如，
the firm that you used to work at.
你曾经工作的公司。
And actually even that's got it inside,
实际上即使它已经内部，
the smaller noun phrase,
小名词短语，
which is just the word you.
这就是你的话。
So an individual pronoun is also a noun phrase.
因此，个体代词也是名词短语。
Um, so just kind of structuring of
嗯，所以只是一种结构
language where you get this sort of
你得到这种语言的语言
hierarchical structure and the same kind of things inside them.
层次结构和它们内部的同类事物。
I think that's just sort of totally, totally correct.
我认为这完全是完全正确的。
Um, the- the claim then that,
嗯，那个说法，那个，
you know, our language is recursive, I mean,
你知道，我的语言是递归的，我的意思是，
in a formal sense is not quite clear that that's,
在正式意义上并不十分清楚，那是
uh, it's a clear thing.
呃，这是一个明确的事情。
And that's the reason- to say something is recursive,
这就是为什么说一些东西是递归的，
it has to repeat out to infinity, right.
它必须重复到无限，对。
So as soon as you put any bound on something,
所以只要你对某些东西施加任何限制，
and you say, "Look that's a noun phrase you just gave me with five levels of nesting."
而且你说，“你看这是一个名词短语，你只给了我五层嵌套。”
That's pretty implausible that someone is going to say that.
有人会这么说，这是不可思议的。
And so as soon as you sort of,
所以，只要你这样，
um, want to make an argument like,
嗯，想做个论点，
okay even if they said that,
好吧，即使他们说，
no one is going to say a noun phrase with 10 levels of nesting.
没有人会说出10级嵌套的名词短语。
And if you put some hard limit on it like that, um,
如果你像那样对它施加一些硬限制，嗯，
then in some sense it's not truly recursive because it doesn't go out to infinity.
那么在某种意义上它不是真正的递归，因为它不会出现无穷大。
Um, but, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
regardless what you think about that,
不管你怎么想，
that doesn't negate the basic argument that you get this hierarchical
这并没有否定你得到这种等级的基本论点
structuring with the same kinds of things like noun phrases,
用类似名词短语，
sentences, verb phrases, appearing inside each other in a way that has no clear bound.
句子，动词短语，以一种没有明确界限的方式出现在彼此之内。
Like to the extent that I show you a complex sentence,
就像我向你展示一个复杂的句子，
you can say I can make that an even bigger, more complex sentence by putting it inside,
你可以说我可以通过把它放进去做一个更大，更复杂的句子，
you said to me that, and then saying,
你告诉我那个，然后说，
um, my sentence, right.
嗯，我的判决，对。
So that's the sense in which it does appear to be a recursive generative process,
所以这就是它看起来像一个递归的生成过程的意义，
even though practically there are limits to how complex sentences people say.
尽管人们说的复杂句子实际上是有限的。
And so that's the kind of structure that gets
这就是那种结构
captured in these constituency, um, structure trees.
在这些选区中捕获，嗯，结构树。
So before the early time when we talked about parsing and you guys did some of it,
所以在我们谈论解析的早期之前，你们做了一些，
I emphasized dependency parsing.
我强调了依赖解析。
Um, but the other kind of parsing which is actually
嗯，但实际上是另一种解析
the kind that the models I'm going to talk about today was using,
那个我今天要讨论的模型正在使用的那种，
was this idea of what's often called constituency
这是什么通常被称为选区的想法
parsing or linguists often call it phrase structure grammars,
解析或语言学家经常称它为短语结构语法，
um, or in sort of computer science formal language theory.
嗯，或者说是某种计算机科学的形式语言理论。
These are context-free grammars, where, um,
这些是无上下文的语法，其中，嗯，
we're having, um, these,
我们有，嗯，这些，
um, non-terminals like noun phrase,
嗯，像名词短语这样的非终端，
and verb phrase, and that's inside another noun phrases,
和动词短语，那是在另一个名词短语里面，
it's inside another verb phrase,
它在另一个动词短语里面，
which is inside more verb phrases,
这是更多的动词短语，
heading up the sentence.
领导这句话。
And so these are our constituency grammars.
所以这些是我们的选区语法。
And when we've occasionally mentioned the Penn Treebank tree,
当我们偶尔提到Penn Treebank树时，
this was kind of an original Penn Treebank tree which is basically, uh,
这是一种原始的Penn Treebank树，基本上，呃，
phrase structure grammar like,
短语结构语法，如，
this with sort of various extra annotations,
这有各种额外的注释，
um, put on the nodes.
嗯，穿上节点。
Okay, so what did seem- what- what do you- to capture some of these properties,
好的，那么看起来什么 - 你有什么 - 捕获一些这些属性，
it seems like we'd like to have a neural model
好像我们想要一个神经模型
that can make use of some of this same kind of tree structure.
可以利用这种相同类型的树结构。
And so what we'd like to do for working out semantic similarity of constituents,
那么我们想要做些什么来制定成分的语义相似性，
is we want to not only have
我们不仅希望拥有
a word vector space like we started off with right at the beginning of the quarter,
一个单词向量空间就像我们在季度开始时一样，
but we'd like to be able to take bigger constituents like noun phrases,
但我们希望能够采取更大的成分，如名词短语，
the country of my birth,
我出生的国家，
and the place where I was born,
和我出生的地方，
and also give them a meaning.
并给他们一个意义。
And so it seems like what we'd like to do is have a method of
所以我们想要做的就是有一种方法
computing the meaning of any phrase in a compositional manner,
以组合方式计算任何短语的含义，
such that the end result is also that
这样最终结果也是如此
these phrases could be stuck inside our vector space models.
这些短语可能会卡在我们的矢量空间模型中。
So we're still going to stick with our vector space semantics of phrases,
所以我们仍然会坚持使用短语的向量空间语义，
and we wanna comp- compute the meanings of phrases.
我们想要计算短语的含义。
And so then the question is,
那么问题是，
how could we go about doing that?
我们怎么能这样做呢？
And well answer number one is we're gonna use the principle of
第一，我们将使用原则
compositionality since we're sure it's right,
因为我们确定它是正确的，
and so, well, what the principle of compositionality essentially says,
那么，组合性原则本质上是什么，
if you want to work out the meaning- or here it says of a sentence.
如果你想弄清楚意思 - 或者在这里说出一句话。
But the meaning of any phrase, any constituent is you're going to
但任何一个短语的含义，任何成分都是你要去的
build it by knowing the meanings of its words,
通过了解其词义来建立它，
and then having rules that combine these meanings.
然后制定结合这些含义的规则。
So starting off with the country of my birth,
所以从我出生的国家开始，
I should be able to calculate a meaning of my birth,
我应该能够计算出生的意义，
and meaning of the country,
和国家的意义，
and meaning of of the- my birth and then a meaning of the country of my birth.
和我的出生的意义，然后是我出生的国家的意义。
So we'd have meaning composition rules which will let us calculate
所以我们有意义组合规则让我们计算
meanings upwards for larger constituents or sentences.
较大的成分或句子的意义向上。
Um, so that seems kind of the right thing to do.
嗯，所以这似乎是正确的事情。
And so then the question is well, can we, um,
那么问题就好了，我们可以，嗯，
then build a model of how to do that?
然后建立一个如何做到这一点的模型？
Well, here's sort of a straightforward way of doing this, okay.
嗯，这是一种直截了当的方式，好吧。
So we- we have word vectors for the words that we've calculated.
所以我们 - 我们为我们计算的单词提供了单词向量。
And what we'd like to do is work out, um-
而我们想要做的就是锻炼，嗯 -
Then a meaning representation of this sentence.
然后是这句话的意思表示。
And at this point we sort of have two things to do.
在这一点上，我们有两件事要做。
We have parsing to do of working out what's the right structure of the sentence,
我们已经解析了如何解决句子的正确结构，
and then we have meaning computation to do of
然后我们有意义计算
working out what is the meaning representation of this sentence.
弄清楚这句话的意思是什么。
Um, so for parsing we'd sort of be building,
嗯，所以对于解析我们有点建设，
sort of noun phrase, prepositional phrase,
一种名词短语，介词短语，
verb phrase, sentence kind of units, um,
动词短语，句子类型，嗯，
to get "the cat sat on the mat",
得到“猫坐在垫子上”，
and then will, what,
什么，
we, if we had that,
我们，如果有的话，
we could then run some kind of meaning computation program,
然后我们可以运行某种意义计算程序，
and give us sort of a vector space,
并给我们一个矢量空间，
um, meaning of these sentences.
嗯，这些句子的意思。
So that's kind of what we want,
这就是我们想要的东西，
is to do both of those,
是做这两个，
and in a little bit I'll show you an example of the kind
稍后我会告诉你一个这样的例子
of one way that you go about approaching that.
一种方式，你去接近那个。
But before I do that, just sort of stepping back for
但在我这样做之前，只是退一步
a moment as to what's different here, right?
关于这里有什么不同的时刻，对吧？
That here we had our
我们在这里有我们的
recurrent neural network which in some sense has been
在某种意义上已经存在的递归神经网络
our workhorse tool in this class up to now,
到目前为止，我们这个班级的主力工具，
and it gives you,
它给了你，
it gives you a representation of the meaning of the country of my birth sort of,
它为您提供了我的出生国家的意义，
you could either say that's the meaning of,
你可以说这是意思，
um, the country of my birth,
嗯，我出生的国家，
or we talked about other tricks like,
或者我们谈过其他技巧，比如
doing max pooling across all of these,
在所有这些中进行最大池化，
or you could have a separate node out here,
或者你可以在这里有一个单独的节点，
which so does attention over these.
对这些人的关注也是如此。
So it does give you a sort of representation, um,
所以它确实给你一种表现，嗯，
of the meaning of this,
这个意思，
of any, um, sub-sequence of words as well.
任何，嗯，字的子序列。
Um, but they, they're sort of different, right?
嗯，但他们，他们有点不同，对吧？
That this what, the top,
这是什么，顶部，
the tree recursive neural network,
树递归神经网络，
it requires a sentence or any kind of phrase to have a tree structure.
它需要一个句子或任何类型的短语来具有树结构。
So we know what its component parts are,
所以我们知道它的组成部分是什么，
but then we're working out meaning representations
但后来我们正在制定意义陈述
for the phrase that is sensitive to what its syntactic structure is,
对于对其句法结构敏感的短语，
that how the words go together to build phrases.
这些单词如何组合在一起构建短语。
Whereas for the recurrent neural network we're
而对于递归神经网络，我们是
just in an oblivious way running a sequence model along,
只是以一种不经意的方式运行序列模型，
and say and compute things,
说和计算的东西，
and in the obvious,
在显而易见的
it doesn't in any obvious way give a meaning representation of,
它没有任何明显的方式给出一个含义，
of my birth, or my birth contained inside that.
我的出生，或者我的出生包含在那里。
We sort of only have a meaning representation for the whole sequence,
我们只对整个序列有一个含义表示，
whereas if we're doing things this way, um,
如果我们这样做，嗯，
we do have meaning representations for the different meaningful parts of the sentence.
我们对句子的不同有意义部分有意义表示。
Okay. That makes sense of what we're trying to do?
好的。这是我们想要做的事情的意义吗？
Okay. So how could we do,
好的。那我们该怎么做呢
go about doing that?
那样做呢？
Um, well, the idea of how we could go about doing that is,
嗯，我们如何做到这一点的想法是，
if we work bottom-up,
如果我们自下而上工作，
at the very bottom we have word vectors,
在最底层我们有单词向量，
and so we want to recursively compute the meaning of bigger constituents.
所以我们想要递归地计算更大的成分的意义。
So if we wanted to compute the meaning of "on the mat" what we can do is say,
因此，如果我们想要计算“在垫子上”的含义，我们可以做的就是说，
well, we have, already have a meaning representation of, on and mat.
好吧，我们已经有了，on和mat的含义。
So if we could feed those into a neural network, because that's our
因此，如果我们可以将它们提供给神经网络，因为那是我们的
one tool, we could maybe get out of it two things.
一个工具，我们可以从中得到两件事。
We could get out of it a goodness score.
我们可以从中获得良好的分数。
So this is what we're going to use for parsing.
这就是我们将要用于解析的内容。
We're going to say, "Do you belie- do you believe you can put together "on" and the
我们会说，“你相信 - 你相信你可以把”放在一起“和”
"mat" to form a good constituent that's part of a parse tree?
“席子”是否构成了解析树的一部分？
And this will be a big positive number if the answer is true,
如果答案是真的，这将是一个很大的正数，
and negative if it's not true,
如果不是这样，则为负数，
and then we have a meaning composition device,
然后我们有一个意义组合设备，
which says, "Okay, um,
它说，“好的，嗯，
if you put together these two things,
如果你把这两件事放在一起，
what would be the meaning representation of what we put together?"
我们放在一起的意义是什么呢？“
And so this is the first model that we explored which
所以这是我们探索的第一个模型
was doing this in a pretty simple way, right?
这是以一种非常简单的方式做到的，对吗？
So here was our meaning composition, um,
所以这是我们的意思构成，嗯，
device that we concatenated the two vectors of the constituents,
我们连接成分的两个向量的设备，
we multiply them by a matrix, add a
我们将它们乘以矩阵，加上一个
bias as usual,
像往常一样偏见，
put it through a tan h. Uh,
穿过棕褐色。呃，
this work is old enough,
这项工作已经够老了，
it's sort of before things, like,
它有点像事情，比如，
ReLUs became popular,
ReLU开始流行，
but maybe it's better to have a tan h anyway, um, fit more like,
但也许最好还是晒黑，嗯，更适合，
a recurrent neural network,
一个递归神经网络，
and so this was our meaning composition that gave the meaning of the parent.
所以这是我们的意思构成，赋予了父母的意义。
And then to the side, what the score of it was as to whether this was a good phrase,
然后在旁边，它的得分是否是一个好词，
we were taking that parent vector representation,
我们正在采用父矢量表示，
and multiplying it by another vector,
并将其乘以另一个向量，
and that was giving us out a number.
那就是给我们一个数字。
Um, if you think about it a bit while we're doing this,
嗯，如果你在我们这样做的时候考虑一​​下，
you might think that this isn't quite a perfect model of meaning composition,
你可能会认为这不是一个完美的意义构成模型，
and later on in the class I'll talk about some more complex models,
然后在课堂上我会谈到一些更复杂的模型，
um, that we then started to explore.
嗯，我们开始探索。
Um, but this is sort of enough to get us going,
嗯，但这足以让我们前进，
and this gave us a way of building
这给了我们一种建设方式
a recursive neural network parser which both found parsers,
一个递归的神经网络解析器，它都找到了解析器，
and worked out a meaning representation for them.
并为他们制定了意义表示。
And so the way we did this was in the simplest possible way really,
所以我们这样做的方式是以最简单的方式，
which was to have a greedy parser.
这是一个贪婪的解析器。
So if we start off with the "cat sat on the mat",
所以，如果我们从“猫坐在垫子上”开始，
what we could do is say,
我们能做的就是说，
well, maybe you should join "the" and "cat" together.
好吧，也许你应该加入“the”和“cat”。
Let's try that.
我们试试吧。
Run it through our neural network,
通过我们的神经网络运行它，
it'll get a score and a meaning representation,
它会获得分数和意义表示，
and while we could try doing that for "cat" and
虽然我们可以尝试为“猫”而做
"sat" we could try doing it for "sat" and "on".
“坐”我们可以尝试为“坐”和“开”。
We could try doing it for "on" and "the" we could try doing it for "the" and "mat".
我们可以尝试“on”和“the”，我们可以尝试为“the”和“mat”做这件事。
And then at this point we'd say, okay, well the,
然后在这一点上我们会说，好吧，好吧，
the best phrase that we can make combining these word vectors is the one for "the cat".
我们可以结合这些单词向量的最佳短语是“猫”。
So let's just commit to that one,
所以，让我们承诺那个，
and it has this semantic representation,
它有这种语义表示，
and at this point we can essentially repeat.
在这一点上，我们可以基本上重复。
Now, all the work we did over there we can just reuse because nothing has changed,
现在，我们在那里所做的所有工作都可以重复使用，因为没有任何改变，
but we can also consider now joining the "cat"
但我们现在也可以考虑加入“猫”
as a constituent with "sat" and get a score for that.
作为“sat”的成分并获得分数。
And so at this point we decide, okay,
所以在这一点上我们决定，好吧，
the mat is the best constituent to build,
垫子是构建的最佳组成部分，
commit to that, calculate a meaning representation for "on the mat".
承诺，计算“在垫子上”的含义表示。
That looks good, commit to that,
看起来很好，承诺，
and kind of keep on chugging up,
并继续喋喋不休，
and so we've got a mechanism for sort of choosing a parse of a sentence in a,
所以我们有一种机制来选择一个句子的解析，
in a greedy manner.
贪得无厌
But, you know, when we looked at the dependency parsing,
但是，你知道，当我们查看依赖解析时，
we're also doing that greedily, right?
我们也贪婪地这样做，对吧？
Um, and coming up with a meaning representation.
嗯，并想出一个意义表示。
Okay. So that was our first model of having a tree recursive neural network,
好的。这是我们第一个拥有树递归神经网络的模型，
and using it for parsing.
并使用它进行解析。
Um, there are a few more details here,
嗯，这里还有一些细节，
some of which probably aren't super,
其中一些可能不是超级的，
um, important at this point, right?
嗯，在这一点上很重要，对吧？
So we could score a tree by summing the scores at each node,
所以我们可以通过总结每个节点的得分来得分树，
um, for working out,
嗯，为了锻炼，
for the optimization we were working out,
为了优化我们正在努力，
we're using this kind of max-margin loss that we've looked at in other places.
我们正在使用我们在其他地方看过的这种最大边际损失。
Um, the simplest way to do things is completely greedily.
嗯，最简单的做事方式是贪得无厌。
You just, um, find the best local decision at each point,
你，嗯，在每个点找到最好的当地决定，
and make that structure,
并使这个结构，
and keep on going.
并继续前进。
But if you wanna do things a bit better,
但如果你想做得更好一点，
and we explored this,
我们探索了这个，
um, you could say,
嗯，你可以说，
um, we could do beam search.
嗯，我们可以进行光束搜索。
We could explore out several good ways of merging,
我们可以探索几种合并的好方法，
and then decide later higher up the tree as to which was the best way, um, to merge.
然后决定以后更高的树，哪个是合并的最佳方式。
Um, we haven't talked about it in this class,
嗯，我们在这堂课里没有谈过这个，
but just to mention, um,
但是，嗯，嗯，
something in case people have seen it is, um,
人们已经看到它的一些事情，嗯，
traditional constituency parsing where you have symbols here,
传统选区解析你在哪里有符号，
like, NP or VP.
比如，NP或VP。
Um, there exist efficient dynamic programming algorithms where you can
嗯，你可以在那里使用高效的动态编程算法
find the optimal parse of a sentence in polynomial time.
在多项式时间内找到句子的最佳解析。
So in, in cubic time.
因此，在立方时间内。
So if you have a regular context-free grammar, and well,
所以，如果你有一个常规的无上下文语法，那么，
so regular probabilistic context-free grammar, um,
所以常规的概率上下文语法，嗯，
and if you want to know what is the best parse of
如果你想知道什么是最好的解析
the sentence according to the probabilistic context-free grammar,
根据概率上下文无关语法的句子，
you can write a cubic time dynamic programming algorithm and you can find it.
你可以写一个立方时间动态编程算法，你可以找到它。
That's good. And in the old days of CS224N,
非常好。在CS224N的旧时代，
um, before neural networks we used to have everyone do that.
嗯，在神经网络之前，我们曾经让每个人都这样做。
The, the most, the most brain-breaking assignment of the old CS224N
旧CS224N的最大，最突兀的任务
was writing this dynamic program to do context-free grammar parsing of a sentence.
正在编写这个动态程序来对句子进行无上下文语法分析。
Um, the slightly sad fact is,
嗯，有点可悲的是，
once you go to these kind of neural network representations,
一旦你进入这种神经网络表示，
you can't write clever dynamic programming algorithms anymore,
你不能再编写聪明的动态编程算法了，
because clever dynamic programming algorithms only work when you have symbols
因为聪明的动态编程算法只有在你有符号时才有用
from a reasonably small set for your non-terminals because if that's the case,
从你的非终端的一个相当小的集合，因为如果是这样的话，
you can, you kind of have collisions, right?
你可以，你有碰撞，对吧？
You have lots of ways of parsing stuff lower down,
你有很多解析东西的方法，
which kind of, uh,
哪种，呃，
turn out to be different ways to make a noun phrase,
结果是制作名词短语的不同方法，
or different ways to make a prepositional phrase,
或制作介词短语的不同方式，
and therefore you can save work with dynamic programming.
因此，您可以使用动态编程来节省工作。
If you've got a model like this,
如果你有这样的模特，
since everything that you build is going through layers of neural network,
因为你构建的所有内容都是通过层次的神经网络，
and you've got a meaning representation, some high-dimensional vector,
你有一个意义表示，一些高维向量，
things are never going to collide,
事物永远不会碰撞，
and so you can never save work by doing dynamic programming.
所以你永远不能通过动态编程来节省工作。
And so, um, you're either doing exponential work to explore out everything,
所以，嗯，你要么做指数工作来探索一切，
or else you're using some kind of beam to explore a bunch of likely stuff.
或者你正在使用某种光束来探索一堆可能的东西。
Yeah. Um, we actually also applied this,
是啊。嗯，我们其实也应用了这个，
um, to vision at the same time.
嗯，同时有远见。
So it wasn't just sort of completely
所以它不仅仅是完全的
a vague motivation of, um,
一个模糊的动机，嗯，
visual scenes have parts that we actually started exploring that well you could take, um,
视觉场景有我们真正开始探索的部分，你可以采取，嗯，
these pieces of scenes and then work out, um,
这些场景然后解决，嗯，
representations for scenes using a similar form of compositionality.
使用类似形式的组合的场景的表示。
And so in particular,
特别是，
um, there was sort of this dataset that was being used for, um,
嗯，有一些这个数据集正在用于，嗯，
multi-class segmentation in vision,
视觉中的多级分割，
where you start off with very small patches and then you wanna combine them
你从非常小的补丁开始，然后你想要结合它们
up into parts of a scene of sort of
到某种场景的某些部分
recognizing which part of the picture was the building,
认识到图片的哪一部分是建筑物，
the sky, the road, various other classes.
天空，道路，各种其他类。
And we were actually at the time able to do this really rather well, um,
我们当时真的很能做到这一点，嗯，
using one of these tree recursive structured neural networks better
更好地使用这些树递归结构化神经网络之一
than preceding work in vision had done in the late 2000s decade.
比起之前的视觉工作已经在21世纪后期进行了。
Okay. So how can we- how can we build neural networks,
好的。那么我们怎样才能建立神经网络，
um, that do this kind of stuff?
嗯，这样做的东西？
Um, so when- when we started off exploring these tree structured neural networks, um,
嗯，所以当我们开始探索这些树状结构神经网络的时候，嗯，
we thought that this was a cool original idea and no one
我们认为这是一个很酷的原创想法，没有人
had worked on tree structured neural networks successfully before.
以前成功地在树结构神经网络上工作过。
Um, but it turned out we were wrong, that there were a couple of Germans in the mid-1990s,
嗯，但事实证明我们错了，在20世纪90年代中期有几个德国人，
um, had actually started looking at tree structured neural networks and had worked out,
嗯，实际上已经开始研究树状结构神经网络并且已经解决了，
um, the math of them.
嗯，他们的数学。
So corresponding to the backpropagation through time algorithm,
因此对应于通过时间算法的反向传播，
um, that Abby talked about when we were doing recurrent neural networks.
嗯，Abby谈到我们做反复神经网络的时候。
They worked out the tree structured case which they
他们制定了树形结构的案例
called backpropagation, um, through structure.
称为反向传播，嗯，通过结构。
Um, there are several slides on this in
嗯，这里有几张幻灯片
the slides but I think I'm gonna sort of skip them.
幻灯片，但我想我会跳过它们。
If anyone wants to look at them,
如果有人想看看他们，
they're on the web and you can look at them.
他们在网上，你可以看看他们。
I mean, there isn't actually anything that's new.
我的意思是，实际上没有什么是新的。
So if you remember with- with
所以，如果你还记得
bad scarring or something that was early lectures of this class of working out,
糟糕的疤痕或早期讲授这类锻炼的东西，
um, the derivatives of neural networks and how it worked with recurrent neural networks.
嗯，神经网络的衍生物以及它如何与递归神经网络一起工作。
It's sort of the same, right.
它是一样的，对吧。
You have this recurrent matrix at different levels of tree structure.
您在树结构的不同级别具有此循环矩阵。
You're summing the derivatives of everywhere it turns up.
你总结了它所到之处的衍生物。
The only difference is sort of because we now have tree structure,
唯一的区别是因为我们现在有树结构，
you're sort of splitting things downwards.
你有点向下分裂。
Um, so yes.
嗯，是的。
So forward prop we kind of compute it forwards.
所以前进道具我们有点计算它前进。
And then when we're doing back prop,
然后当我们做背部道具时，
when we've had the backward propagation we have the error signal coming from above.
当我们进行了向后传播时，我们会得到来自上方的误差信号。
We then, um, combine it,
那么，我们，把它结合起来，
um, with the calculations at this node.
嗯，在这个节点上进行计算。
And then we're sort of sending it back in a tree structure
然后我们将它发送回树形结构中
down to each of the branches underneath us.
到我们下面的每个分支。
So that was our first version of things and we got some decent results.
这是我们的第一个版本的东西，我们得到了一些不错的结果。
We got this good vision results that I showed you and it sort of seemed to do,
我给你看了这个好的视力结果，它似乎有点像，
um, some good for, um,
嗯，有些好，嗯，
language both for parsing and doing- We had
解析和做的语言 - 我们有
some results I haven't actually included here of sort of doing paraphrase,
一些结果我实际上并没有包含这样的解释，
um, judgment between sentences and it- it modeled things, um, fairly well.
嗯，句子和它之间的判断 - 它模仿了事物，嗯，相当不错。
But once we started thinking about it more it seemed like
但是，一旦我们开始考虑它，它似乎就像
that very simple neural net function couldn't possibly
那种非常简单的神经网络功能是不可能的
compute the kind of meanings that we wanted to compute for sentence meanings.
计算我们想要为句子意义计算的那种意义。
And so we then sort of set about trying to come up with
因此，我们接下来试图提出
some more complex ways of working out kind
一些更复杂的方法
of meaning composition functions and nodes that
意义组合函数和节点
could then be used to build a better neural network.
然后可以用来建立一个更好的神经网络。
And sort of some- some of the essence of that is on this slide.
还有一些本质的一部分就是这张幻灯片。
But, you know, for the first version we just
但是，你知道，对于我们的第一个版本
didn't have enough complexity of neural network, frankly, right?
坦率地说，没有足够复杂的神经网络，对吧？
So when we had two constituents we concatenated
因此，当我们有两个成分时，我们会连接起来
them and multiply that by a weight, uh, weight matrix.
它们乘以重量，呃，重量矩阵。
Um, and that was sort of essentially all we had.
嗯，这基本上就是我们所拥有的一切。
And, um, as I hope you've gotten more of a sense of in this class.
而且，嗯，因为我希望你在这堂课上有更多的感觉。
If you just concatenate and multiply by a weight matrix,
如果你只是连接并乘以权重矩阵，
you're not actually modeling the interaction between these two vectors, right.
你实际上并没有模拟这两个向量之间的相互作用，对吧。
Because you can think of this weight matrix as just sort of being
因为你可以把这个权重矩阵想象成一种存在
divided in two and half of it multiplies this vector,
分成两半，它乘以这个向量，
and half of it multiplies this vector.
它的一半乘以这个向量。
So the meanings of these two things don't act on each other.
所以这两件事的意义并不相互作用。
And so somehow you have to make your neural network,
所以你不得不建立你的神经网络，
um, more complex than that.
嗯，比那更复杂。
But the other way in which this seemed too simple is in the first model,
但另一种看似太简单的方式是在第一个模型中，
we had just one weight matrix which we use for everything.
我们只有一个重量矩阵，我们用它来做所有事情。
And, ah, at least if you're a linguist and you're
啊，至少如果你是一名语言学家而且你是
thinking about the structure of language you might start thinking of well,
思考你可能开始思考的语言结构，
wait a minute, sometimes you're gonna be putting
等一下，有时候你会放
together a verb and an object noun phrase.
一起动词和一个对象名词短语。
Um, hit the ball.
嗯，击球。
Sometimes you're gonna be putting together an article and a noun, uh, ball.
有时你会把一篇文章和一个名词，呃，球放在一起。
Sometimes you're gonna be doing adjectival modification blue ball.
有时候你会做一些形容词修饰蓝球。
These things are very different in their semantics.
这些东西在语义上是非常不同的。
Can it really be the case that you can just have one weight matrix that is
你真的可以拥有一个权重矩阵吗？
this universal composition function for putting together the meaning of phrases?
这个通用的组合功能，用于拼写短语的含义？
Could that possibly work?
这可能有用吗？
And you sort of might suspect,
你有点怀疑，
um, it doesn't work.
嗯，它不起作用。
Um, and so I'm gonna go on and, um,
嗯，所以我会继续，嗯，
show, um, some of those different things.
显示，嗯，其中一些不同的东西。
But really, um, before I show the different things,
但是，真的，嗯，在我展示不同的东西之前，
um, I'm gonna show one more version that's sort of related to the first thing,
嗯，我要再显示一个与第一件事有关的版本，
which actually gave a pretty successful and good parser,
这实际上给了一个非常成功和良好的解析器，
um, for doing, um,
嗯，干嘛，嗯，
context-free style constituency parsing.
无上下文风格选区解析。
And so this was another way of getting away from the parsing being completely greedy.
所以这是摆脱解析完全贪婪的另一种方式。
Um, which was to actually split apart the two parts of g. We
嗯，实际上是将g的两个部分分开了。我们
have to come up with a tree structure for our sentence from,
必须为我们的句子想出一个树形结构，
'Let's compute the meaning of the sentence'.
'让我们计算句子的意思'。
And so the thinking was, well,
所以这个想法是，好吧，
in terms of deciding what's a good tree structure for a sentence,
在决定一个句子的好树结构方面，
that's actually something you can do pretty well with the symbolic grammar.
这实际上是你可以用符号语法做得很好的东西。
But the problems with symbolic grammars aren't
但符号语法的问题却不是
that they can't put tree structures over sentences.
他们不能把树结构放在句子上。
The problems you have with those grammars is that,
你对这些语法的问题是，
they can't compute meaning representation and they're not
他们不能计算意义表示而他们不能
very good at choosing between alternative tree structures.
非常擅长在替代树结构之间进行选择。
But we can divide up the two parts.
但我们可以将这两部分分开。
So what we can do is say, well,
所以我们能做的就是说，好吧，
let's just use a regular probabilistic Context-Free Grammar
让我们使用常规的概率无上下文语法
to generate possible tree structures for sentences.
为句子生成可能的树结构。
We can generate a k best list and say,
我们可以生成ak最佳列表并说，
what are the 50 best, um,
什么是最好的50，嗯，
context-free grammar structures for this sentence?
这句话的无上下文语法结构？
And that's something we can do very efficiently with dynamic programming algorithms.
这是我们可以通过动态编程算法非常有效地完成的事情。
And then we can work out a neural net,
然后我们可以找出一个神经网络，
um, that will work out the meaning representation of the sentence.
嗯，这将解决句子的意义表示。
Um, and so that led to this, um,
嗯，这导致了这个，嗯，
what's called syntactically untied recursive neural network.
什么叫做语法解开的递归神经网络。
Um, so essentially what this is saying is that we
嗯，基本上这就是说我们
ha- for each node and the sentence it's got a category,
ha-对于每个节点和句子都有一个类别，
um, of a symbolic context-free grammar.
嗯，一个象征性的无语境语法。
So they're category A and B and C. So when
所以他们是A，B和C类。所以
we put things together we'll be able to say, okay.
我们把事情放在一起，我们可以说，好的。
We've got a rule that says, um,
我们有一条规则说，嗯，
X goes to BC,
X去了BC，
so that licenses this node here.
所以在这里许可这个节点。
So that part of the parsing is symbolic.
所以解析的一部分是象征性的。
Then- then we want to, um,
然后 - 我们想，嗯，
work out the meaning of this phrase.
弄清楚这句话的意思。
Um, and well, the second problem I talked about
嗯，好吧，我谈到的第二个问题
was surely just having a one way of doing composition
肯定只是一种做作文的方式
is expecting a lot too much to be able to have
期待能够拥有太多的东西
sort of verb and object versus adjective and noun composed the same way.
动词和宾语与形容词和名词的组合方式相同。
So we have this idea of well,
所以我们有这个想法，
since we now know about the syntactic categories of
因为我们现在知道了语法的类别
the children that we maybe know that this is an adjective and this is a noun.
孩子们，我们可能知道这是一个形容词，这是一个名词。
What we could do is have different weight matrices for
我们能做的是有不同的权重矩阵
composition depending on what the categories are.
组成取决于类别。
So rather than where before there was
所以而不是之前的地方
just this one universal weight matrix which was meant to do all meaning composition.
只是这一个通用的权重矩阵，意味着做所有意义的组合。
Here we can have,
我们可以在这里，
this is the weight matrix for combining together
这是组合在一起的权重矩阵
the meanings of an adjective and a noun and it will compute,
形容词和名词的含义，它会计算，
um, the meaning of this constituent.
嗯，这个成分的含义。
But then we'll have a different weight matrix for combining
但是我们将有一个不同的权重矩阵进行组合
together the meanings of a determiner and a noun phrase or something like that.
一起确定者和名词短语的含义或类似的东西。
Okay. Um, yes.
好的。嗯，是的。
So I sort of always said this one I guess,
所以我总是说这个我猜，
um, we wanted to be able to do things quickly.
嗯，我们希望能够快速做事。
And so our solution to be able to do that is we sort of
所以我们能够做到这一点的解决方案就是我们
used a probabilistic context-free grammar to find likely parses,
使用概率上下文无关语法来查找可能的解析，
um, and then only worked out our meaning for ones that were, um, quite probable.
嗯，然后只为那些很有可能的人找出了我们的意思。
And so we call this result a compositional vector grammar which was
所以我们将这个结果称为组合矢量语法
a combination of a PCFG and a tree recursive neural network.
PCFG和树递归神经网络的组合。
Um, and yeah.
嗯，是的
So, um, essentially at the time,
所以，嗯，基本上当时，
this actually gave a pretty good constituency parser.
这实际上给了一个非常好的选区解析器。
So there are sort of lots of results here.
所以这里有很多结果。
The top ones are kind of our classic older, um,
顶级的是我们经典的老年人，嗯，
Stanford Parser which is a PCFG,  the kind of parsers that people had built.
Stanford Parser是PCFG，是人们建造的解析器。
This is our compositional vector grammar that the time of this being done in 2013,
这是我们的组合矢量语法，这个时间是在2013年完成的，
it wasn't the very best parser available.
它不是最好的解析器。
There had been some better work by Eugene Charniak at Brown.
布朗的Eugene Charniak做了一些更好的工作。
But we actually had a pretty good parser coming out of that system.
但是我们实际上有一个非常好的解析器来自该系统。
But what was perhaps a bit more interesting was we,
但是我们可能更有趣的是，
we didn't only have a parser that was meant to give the right parse trees.
我们不仅有一个解析器，旨在提供正确的解析树。
We are also computing meaning representations of nodes.
我们还计算节点的意义表示。
And as a kind of a consequence of that,
作为一种结果，
you can look at not only meaning representations of nodes.
你不仅可以看到节点的意义表示。
You could learn about the weight matrices that these models were learning,
你可以了解这些模型正在学习的权重矩阵，
um, when they combine together meanings.
嗯，当他们将意义结合在一起时。
So remember we had these sort of category-specific W matrices,
所以记住我们有这些类别特定的W矩阵，
that were going together with the children to work out the meaning.
与孩子们一起努力解决这个问题。
Um, so these are a little bit hard to interpret.
嗯，所以这些有点难以解释。
But the deal is, when we load these matrices,
但是，当我们加载这些矩阵时，这笔交易是
we initialize them as a pair of diagonal matrices.
我们将它们初始化为一对对角矩阵。
So these are sort of two by one rectangular matrices because there are two children.
所以这些是两个一个矩形矩阵，因为有两个孩子。
Um, so half of it is, um,
嗯，所以有一半是，嗯，
multiplying the left child,
乘以左边的孩子，
the other half is multiplying the right child.
另一半正在增加正确的孩子。
And we initialize them as sort of like a compi- two identity matrices next to each
我们将它们初始化为类似于每个旁边的复杂身份矩阵
other which would give us the sort of default semantics
其他会给我们提供默认语义的
of just averaging until something different was learned in the,
只是平均，直到学到了不同的东西，
in the, in the weight vectors.
在，在权重向量中。
And to the extent that sort of nothing interesting has been learned by the model,
并且在某种程度上，模型没有学到任何有趣的东西，
you'll get yellow along the diagonal and this sort of sky blue in the rest of the field.
你将沿着对角线变黄，这种天蓝色在其他地方。
And to the extent that it's learned something
并且在某种程度上，它学到了一些东西
interesting to take out of the semantics of a child,
有趣的是取出孩子的语义，
you will then start to see reds and oranges on the diagonal,
然后你会开始看到对角线上的红色和橙色，
and dark blues and greens and stuff in the rest of the field.
和其他领域的深蓝色和绿色和东西。
So what you find is that if you train this model,
所以你发现如果你训练这个模型，
it's learning about which children of a phrase are actually the important ones.
它正在学习一个短语的哪些孩子实际上是重要的。
Um, so these ones are saying that if you're
嗯，所以这些人说如果你是
combining together a noun phrase and the coordination,
将名词短语和协调结合在一起，
so something like "the cat and",
所以像“猫和”，
that most of the semantics have to be found in "the cat"
大多数语义必须在“猫”中找到
and not much of the semantics is going to be found in "and".
并没有太多的语义将在“和”中找到。
Whereas if you are combining together a possessive pronoun,
如果你把所有格代词组合在一起，
something like her or his,
像她或他的东西，
um, with a noun phrase inside it like,
嗯，里面有一个名词短语，
um, her tabby cat or something like that.
嗯，她的虎斑猫或类似的东西。
Then most of the meaning is to be found inside the tabby cat constituent.
然后大部分的意思是在虎斑猫成分中找到。
So it's actually learning where the important semantics of sentences is.
所以它实际上是在学习句子的重要语义。
Um, and there're lots of examples of that. Um, yeah.
嗯，还有很多例子。嗯，是的
This one sort of- so this one shows a variety of
这一种 - 所以这个显示了各种各样的
modification structures where adjectives or adverbs,
形容词或副词的修饰结构，
um, modify either a noun phrase or an adjective phrase or
嗯，修改名词短语或形容词短语或
just a single adjective is multiplying a noun phrase.
只有一个形容词乘以名词短语。
And the thing that you seem to notice is that there are particular dimensions which are
你似乎注意到的事情是有特定的维度
kind of capturing sort of modification meanings.
有点捕捉某种修饰意义。
So dimension 6 and dimension 11 is sort of showing up in these different,
所以尺寸6和尺寸11有点出现在这些不同的，
um, combinations here, as sort of capturing meaning components.
嗯，这里的组合，作为捕捉意义组件的一种。
So that was kind of neat.
所以这很整洁。
And so this slightly more complex model actually worked pretty
所以这个稍微复杂的模型实际上非常有效
well at capturing a meaning of phrases and sentences.
很好地捕捉短语和句子的含义。
So in this test here,
所以在这个测试中，
we were giving it- the system a test sentence and saying well,
我们给它 - 系统一个测试句并说得好，
what are the other- what are sentences that are most similar in meaning,
什么是其他 - 什么是最相似的句子，
nearest to paraphrases in our corpus for this sentence?
最接近我们语料库中对于这句话的释义？
So if all the figures are adjusted for seasonal variations,
因此，如果所有数字都根据季节变化进行调整，
the two most similar other sentences in the corpus were,
语料库中两个最相似的句子是，
all the numbers are adjusted for seasonal vet fluctuation.
所有数字都根据季节性兽医波动进行调整。
That's a pretty easy one.
这很简单。
Or all the figures are adjusted to remove usual seasonal patterns.
或者调整所有数字以消除通常的季节性模式。
So that seems to be working pretty well.
所以这似乎工作得很好。
"Knight-Ridder wouldn't a comment on the author,
“Knight-Ridder不会对作者发表评论，
Harsco declined to say what country placed the order."
哈斯科拒绝透露哪个国家下订单。“
The semantics there are a bit more different but it
那里的语义有点不同但是它
seems like it is capturing something similar.
好像它正在捕捉类似的东西。
"Um, Coastal wouldn't disclose the terms."
“嗯，Coastal不会透露这些条款。”
That's kind of a really interesting one,
那是一个非常有趣的，
because that one is actually very similar in meaning but it's expressed in
因为那个实际上在意义上非常相似，但它表达的是
a very different way in terms of the words and the syntactic structure that are used.
就所使用的单词和句法结构而言，这是一种非常不同的方式。
Okay, so that was progress because now
好的，所以这是进步，因为现在
we could have different matrices for different constituent types.
我们可以为不同的组成类型使用不同的矩阵。
Um, but there's still some reason to think that we didn't have enough power,
嗯，但仍有一些理由认为我们没有足够的力量，
and that was we're still at heart using this very simple compositional structure
那就是我们仍然在使用这种非常简单的构图结构
where we're just concatenating the two children's vectors and multiplying it by a matrix.
我们只是连接两个孩子的向量并将其乘以矩阵。
So that means the two words, um,
这意味着两个词，嗯，
didn't interact with each other in terms of their meaning.
在意义上没有相互影响。
Um, but, um, it seems like we want to have them interact in their meaning, right?
嗯，但是，嗯，好像我们想要让他们互相交流，对吧？
So in particular if you if you think about
所以特别是如果你想的话
human languages and the kind of things that people look at in linguistic semantics,
人类语言和人们在语言语义学中看到的东西，
you get words that appear to be kind of modifiers or operators.
你会得到一些似乎是修饰语或运算符的单词。
So the word very,
所以这个词非常，
sort of doesn't mean much by itself.
有点并不意味着什么。
I mean it means something like strengthening or more so or something like that,
我的意思是它意味着像强化或类似或类似的东西，
but you know, it doesn't really have a meaning, right?
但是你知道，它确实没有意义，对吧？
It doesn't have any denotation.
它没有任何外延。
You can't show me very things, right?
你不能告诉我很多东西吧？
You can show me chairs and pens and, um,
你可以告诉我椅子和笔，嗯，
children but you can't show me very things,
孩子，但你不能告诉我很多东西，
that the meaning of very seems to be that something comes after it, good.
非常好的意思似乎就是事情发生了，好的。
And this has a sort of an operator meaning of increase on the scale of this thing,
这有一种运算符意味着增加这个东西的规模，
and it can increase on the scale in either direction.
它可以在任何方向上增加规模。
You can have very good or very bad.
你可以有非常好或非常糟糕的。
So if we want to capture that kind of semantics,
所以如果我们想捕获那种语义，
it seems like we can't capture that kind of semantics by just
似乎我们不能仅通过捕获那种语义
concatenating two vectors and multiplying them by a matrix.
连接两个向量并将它们乘以矩阵。
It seems like what we really want to say is very is gonna grab
看起来我们真正想说的就是抓住它
hold of the meaning of good and
掌握好和的意义
modify it in some ways to produce a new meaning for very good.
在某些方面修改它以产生非常好的新意义。
And indeed, that's the kind of approach that's typically,
事实上，这种方法通常是
um, been done in linguistic semantics.
嗯，已经完成了语言语义学。
So in linguistic theories of semantic,
所以在语义学的语言学理论中，
you would normally say, okay,
你通常会说，好的，
good has a meaning,
好有意义，
very is a function that takes in the meaning of good and returns a meaning of very good.
非常是一种功能，它具有良好的意义，并返回非常好的意义。
And so we wanted to have, um,
所以我们想拥有，嗯，
a way of putting that into a neural network.
一种将它放入神经网络的方法。
And so to try and come up with a new composition function as to how to do that.
因此，尝试提出一个新的组合功能，如何做到这一点。
And there are various ways that you could think about
您可以通过各种方式进行思考
doing that and other people have had a couple of different attempts.
这样做，其他人有几个不同的尝试。
But essentially what was in our head is well,
但基本上我们脑子里的东西很好，
we have word vectors,
我们有单词向量，
and if we want to say that very takes the meaning of good and returns a new meaning,
如果我们想说这非常有意义并带来新意义，
the kind of obvious thing to do is to say very
那种显而易见的事情就是说非常
has a matrix attached to it because then we could use the,
有一个矩阵附加到它，因为那时我们可以使用，
the very matrix and multiply it by the good vector and we get a new,
非常矩阵并乘以良好的向量，我们得到一个新的，
um, vector coming out.
嗯，矢量出来了。
And so then, well,
那么，好吧，
the problem is, uh,
问题是，呃，
which- then which words have vectors and which words have matrices?
哪个 - 哪些词有向量，哪些词有矩阵？
And that's kind of, um,
那就是那种，嗯，
hard to know the answer to.
很难知道答案。
I mean, in particular, um,
我的意思是，尤其是，嗯，
words that act as operators can,
作为运营商的话可以，
um, often themselves be modified.
嗯，经常自己被修改。
Um, and so, um, that you know,
嗯，嗯，你知道，
good can also- good also is a operator, right?
好还可以 - 好也是一个运营商，对吗？
So that from a sort of a person,
所以，从某种人，
you can have a good person and that's sort of also an operator,
你可以有一个好人，这也是一个操作员，
and very is modifying that good.
而且正在修改这个好处。
So the idea we came up with is let's not try and predetermine all of this.
所以我们提出的想法是让我们不要尝试预先确定所有这一切。
Why don't we say that every word and every phrase has
为什么我们不说每个词和每个短语都有
connected to it both matrix and vector.
矩阵和矢量都连接到它。
So here's our very good movie.
所以这是我们非常好的电影。
So for each word,
所以对于每个单词，
we have a vector meaning and it has a matrix meaning,
我们有一个矢量意义，它有一个矩阵意义，
and then as we start to build up phrases like very good,
然后我们开始建立非常好的短语，
they're also going to have a vector meaning and a matrix meaning.
它们也将具有矢量意义和矩阵意义。
And so what we proposed was,
所以我们提出的是，
um, so first of all,
嗯，首先，
we, we would like to be able, um,
我们，我们希望能够，嗯，
to calculate, um, the vector meanings.
计算，嗯，向量含义。
So to work out the vector meaning of a phrase like very good.
所以要弄清楚一个非常好的短语的向量含义。
Each word has a matrix meaning.
每个单词都有一个矩阵含义。
And so we're going to combine their opposing matrix and vector meaning.
所以我们将结合他们的对立矩阵和向量意义。
So we're going to take the matrix meaning of
所以我们将采用矩阵的含义
good and multiply it by the vector meaning of very.
好，并乘以非常的矢量意义。
And we're going to take the matrix meaning of very and
我们将采用矩阵的含义
multiply it by the vector meaning of good.
将它乘以良好的向量含义。
And so we're going to have both of those two things.
所以我们将同时拥有这两件事。
And then we're going to have a neural network layer like before that combine those together.
然后我们将像以前一样将神经网络层结合在一起。
And so that's sort of in the red box.
这就是红盒子里的那种。
Then those two things were concatenated,
然后这两件事被连接在一起，
and put through the kind of neural network layer we had before to give us
并通过我们之前提供的那种神经网络层给我们
a final vector meaning on this, for the phrase.
这个短语的最终载体意思就是这个。
And then we also needed a matrix meaning for the phrase.
然后我们还需要这个短语的矩阵含义。
And so for the matrix meaning for the phrase, um.
对于短语的矩阵意义，嗯。
We did this kind of simple model which maybe actually wasn't very good which was to say,
我们做了这种简单的模型，可能实际上并不是很好，也就是说，
let's just concatenate the two matrices of the- um,
让我们简单地连接这两个矩阵，
the constituents, multiply them by
选民，乘以他们
another matrix and that's then going to give us a matrix,
另一个矩阵然后会给我们一个矩阵，
um, version of the parent node.
嗯，父节点的版本。
And so this was gave us our new more compo- more powerful composition procedure.
所以这给了我们新的更强大的组合程序。
Um, this did seem like it could do some kind of good things that captured,
嗯，这似乎可以做一些捕获的好东西，
uh, uh, sort of operator semantics where one word modified the meaning of another word.
呃，呃，一种运算符语义，其中一个单词修饰了另一个单词的含义。
Um, so here's a kind of a neat thing that we were able to do with this.
嗯，所以这是一个我们能够用它做的一件好事。
Um, that we are wanting to be able to work out
嗯，我们希望能够解决这个问题
the semantics of an operator modifying another word.
修改另一个单词的操作符的语义。
So unbelievably annoying, unbelievably awesome, unbelievably sad.
令人难以置信的烦人，令人难以置信的令人难以置信的令人难以置信的悲伤。
Um, not annoying, not awesome, not sad.
嗯，不讨厌，不太棒，不难过。
[NOISE] And so this was contrasting,
[NOISE]所以这是对比的，
our, um, old model versus the new model.
我们，嗯，旧模型与新模型。
And this scale is a scale of positive to negative.
而这个规模是一个积极到消极的尺度。
So this is completely negative to completely positive, all right?
所以这对完全正面完全是消极的，好吗？
And so the kind of contrast you get,
所以你得到的那种对比，
uh, that for, um,
呃，那个，嗯，
not annoying that the simple model thought that this was pretty negative,
并不觉得简单模型认为这是非常消极的，
whereas the new model thinks this is pretty neutral in meaning,
而新模型认为这在意义上是非常中立的，
and that seems to be reasonably correct.
这似乎是合理的正确。
Um, but not sad,
嗯，但不是悲伤，
that means it's a little bit positive and both models were trying to capt- capture that,
这意味着它有点积极，两个模型都试图捕获 - 捕获，
that- you know, the results here are a little bit ambivalent,
你知道，这里的结果有点矛盾，
but- but it sort of seems that they sort of go a
但是 - 但它似乎有点像
little bit in the direction of what we want. Yes.
我们想要的方向一点点。是。
What is the ground truth in the "not sad" example?
“不悲伤”的例子中的基本事实是什么？
Oh, yeah. So this ground truth
哦耶。所以这个基本事实
was- we actually asked a whole bunch of human beings to say,
是 - 我们实际上要求一大群人说，
um, rate the [LAUGHTER] meaning of not sad,
嗯，评价[笑声]不悲伤的意思，
on this scale of 1 to 10.
在这个1至10的范围内。
Maybe this wasn't a very good clear task because as you can see it,
也许这不是一个非常明确的任务，因为你可以看到它，
bounced around a lot [LAUGHTER] as to,
围绕很多[笑声]反弹，
um, what kind of ratings we were getting for things.
嗯，我们得到了什么样的评价。
But yeah, that was actually kind of getting human judgments.
但是，是的，这实际上是一种人类的判断。
Um, we also then use this,
嗯，我们也用这个，
um, model to say, "Well,
嗯，模特说，“嗯，
could we do, um, semantic classification tasks?"
我们能做什么，嗯，语义分类任务？“
So if we wanted to understand relations between different noun phrases,
所以如果我们想要理解不同名词短语之间的关系，
so this was a dataset where, um,
所以这是一个数据集，嗯，
there were relations marked between two noun phrases.
两个名词短语之间存在关系。
My apartment has a pretty large kitchen that that was seen as an example of
我的公寓有一个漂亮的大厨房，被视为一个例子
a component-whole, a part of relationship between the two noun phrases,
一个组件整体，两个名词短语之间的关系的一部分，
and there were other relationships between different kinds of noun phrases.
并且不同类型的名词短语之间存在其他关系。
So if it was the movie showed wars, um,
所以如果电影显示战争，嗯，
that that was then a message topic,
那是一个消息主题，
so there's some communication medium that contains some topic relationship.
所以有一些通信媒介包含一些主题关系。
And so we were using this kind of
所以我们使用这种方式
neural network to sort of build our meaning representations and
神经网络来构建我们的意义表征和
then putting them through
然后把它们穿过
another neural network layer as a classifier to see how well we did.
另一个神经网络层作为分类器，看看我们做得多好。
And so we got some sort of fairly good results on that.
所以我们得到了一些相当不错的结果。
So this was a dataset that people had worked on with
所以这是人们一直在研究的数据集
traditional NLP systems of different kinds of machine learning methods.
传统的NLP系统的各种机器学习方法。
But in some sense, you know,
但从某种意义上说，你知道，
what we were interested in was we seem to be making progress in having
我们感兴趣的是我们似乎在取得进展
a better semantic composition system that
一个更好的语义合成系统
our old recursive neural network was getting about 75 percent,
我们旧的递归神经网络大约增加了75％，
and then our new one was getting about 79 percent,
然后我们新的约占79％，
which we could sort of push up further by putting more features into our system.
我们可以通过在系统中添加更多功能来进一步推进。
So that was progress,
这就是进步，
um, but we didn't stop there.
嗯，但我们并没有就此止步。
We kept on trying to come up with better ways of doing things.
我们一直在努力想出更好的做事方式。
And so even though things worked fairly well here,
所以即使事情在这里运作得相当好，
it sort of seemed like this way of doing matrices wasn't necessarily very good.
看起来这种做矩阵的方式并不一定非常好。
It sort of had two problems.
它有两个问题。
One problem was it introduced a humongous number of parameters because,
一个问题是它引入了大量的参数，因为，
you know, for just about everything that we've done, otherwise,
你知道，对于我们所做的一切，否则，
words have had a vector and well,
单词有一个向量和井，
maybe sometimes we use quite high dimensional vectors like 1,024,
也许有时我们使用相当高的维度向量，如1,024，
um, [NOISE] but, you know, that's a relatively modest number of parameters.
嗯，[NOISE]但是，你知道，这是一个相对适度的参数。
Whereas once we introduce this matrix here,
而一旦我们在这里介绍这个矩阵，
we've got that number of squared additional parameters for every word.
我们为每个单词都有这么多的平方附加参数。
And essentially because of that number of
而且主要是因为这个数字
parameters to be able to compute this model at all,
能够计算这个模型的参数，
we were making the vector size small.
我们使矢量大小变小。
So what we were actually using was that these were
所以我们实际使用的是这些
just 25-dimensional vectors so that the 25 squared,
只有25维向量使25平方，
625, still safe, sort of decently within the range in which we could compute.
625，仍然安全，有点在我们可以计算的范围内。
So that was the first problem.
这是第一个问题。
The second problem is,
第二个问题是，
we didn't really have very good ways of
我们真的没有很好的方法
sort of building up the matrix meaning of bigger phrases.
建立矩阵意义的更大的短语。
I mean, you know,
我的意思是，你知道，
this sort of seems something simple we could do but it didn't,
这种看起来很简单我们可以做但事实并非如此
you know, feel a very good way of getting a matrix meaning of a phrase.
你知道，感觉一种非常好的方法来获得短语的矩阵意义。
So we sort of wanted to come up with some other way of doing
所以我们想要提出一些其他的做法
things that could fix both of those problems.
可以解决这两个问题的事情。
And then, that led into work on recursive neural tensor networks.
然后，这导致了递归神经张量网络的工作。
Um, and there's a kind of a nice idea here of these neural tensors,
嗯，这里有一个关于这些神经张量的好主意，
which is an idea that's actually been used in other places including, um,
这个想法实际上已经在其他地方使用，包括，嗯，
work on sort of putting vector embeddings of knowledge graphs and so on,
研究知识图的嵌入矢量嵌入等等，
which is a kind of a bit of a nice idea.
这是一个很好的主意。
So I wanted to sort of show a bit of how this model works.
所以我想要展示一下这个模型是如何工作的。
Um, and but just to say, first,
嗯，但只是说，首先，
a place where we applied this model was on the problem of sentiment analysis.
我们应用这个模型的地方是关于情绪分析的问题。
Now, I think the term sentiment analysis has come up a few times as something you can
现在，我认为情绪分析一词已经出现了几次
do and actually which I then mentioned in the last, um, lecture.
做，实际上我在上一次，嗯，讲座中提到过。
But I think we've never really talked for five minutes, um,
但我想我们从来没有真正谈过五分钟，嗯，
in this class on sentiment analysis,
在这个关于情绪分析的课堂上，
so I'll, um, give you this as an example of that.
所以我，嗯，给你这个作为一个例子。
Um, sentiment analysis has actually been
嗯，情绪分析实际上已经存在
a really common and important application in natural language processing.
在自然语言处理中非常普遍和重要的应用。
Um, you're looking at a piece of text and you're sort of saying,
嗯，你正在看一段文字，你有点儿说，
"Is it, um, positive or negative?"
“是，呃，是积极的还是消极的？”
Um, and that's just something that's very useful for lots of, um,
嗯，这只是对很多人来说非常有用的东西，嗯，
commercial applications of looking at product reviews or doing brand,
查看产品评论或做品牌的商业应用，
um, awareness and things like that of sort of looking at sentiment connected to things.
嗯，意识和类似于看待与事物相关的情绪的事物。
And to some extent doing sentiment analysis is easy, right?
在某种程度上，做情绪分析很容易，对吧？
That you can kind of say,
你可以说，
"Well, look at a piece of text.
“好吧，看一段文字。
If you see words like loved,
如果你看到喜欢的话，
great, impressed, marvelous, then it's positive.
伟大的，令人印象深刻的，非凡的，然后它是积极的。
It's a positive review.
这是一个积极的评论。
And if it's saying, bad and awful,
如果它说，糟糕而可怕，
then it's a negative review."
然后是负面评论。“
And to some extent that's the baseline of sentiment analysis that you can use
在某种程度上，这是您可以使用的情绪分析的基线
just either selected word features or all words in a bag of words.
只需选择单词功能或单词中的所有单词。
And if you do that,
如果你这样做，
you don't actually do that badly,
你实际上做得不好，
um, in sentiment analysis.
嗯，在情绪分析中。
If you have longer documents,
如果你有更长的文件，
just looking at bags of words can give you 90 percent in sentiment analysis.
只要看一袋文字就可以给你90％的情绪分析。
But on the other hand,
但另一方面，
things often do get trickier, right?
事情往往变得棘手，对吧？
So, um, this is from Rotten Tomatoes.
所以，嗯，这是来自烂番茄。
With this cast and the subject matter,
有了这个演员和主题，
the movie should have been funnier and more entertaining.
电影应该更有趣，更有趣。
And if you sort of pretend you're a bag of words model,
如果你有点假装你是一个单词模型袋，
the only words in this that are sort of clearly sentiment-laden words, uh,
在这里唯一的词语是一种明显充满情感的词，呃，
entertaining and funnier, and both of those are pretty positive words,
娱乐性和有趣性，这些都是非常积极的话，
um, but it's fairly obvious that this actually is meant to be a bad review of the movie.
嗯，但很明显，这实际上是对电影的糟糕评论。
And so well, how are we meant to know that?
那么，我们怎么想知道呢？
Well, it sort of seems again like what we have to do is meaning composition.
好吧，它似乎再次像我们要做的那样意味着构图。
We have to get sort of phrases like "should have been
我们必须得到一些像“本来应该的”这样的短语
funnier," and then realized that that's actually a negative meaning for a phrase.
有趣的，“然后意识到这实际上是一个短语的负面含义。
And so we wanted to explore how we could look at those sort of meanings for
因此，我们想要探索如何看待这些意义
phrases and explore building up those meanings as doing meaning composition over trees.
短语和探索将这些含义构建为对树木的意义构成。
Um, so the first thing we did, um,
嗯，所以我们做的第一件事，嗯，
was we built a treebank of sentiment trees where we got people to rate sentiment.
我们是否建立了一个情感树的树库，我们让人们对情绪进行评价。
And so this led to the Stanford Sentiment Treebank,
所以这导致了斯坦福情感树库，
which is still a dataset you often see used in, um,
这仍然是你经常看到的数据集，嗯，
various of evaluations with a whole bunch of datasets. Indeed,
各种数据集的各种评估。确实，
it showed up in decaNLP last week.
它出现在上周的decaNLP中。
Um, so what we were doing in this was taking,
嗯，所以我们在这里做的是，
um, sentences which were Rotten Tomatoes sentences from movies.
嗯，句子是烂电影中的烂番茄句子。
We were parsing them to give tree structure and then we were asking Mechanical Turkers to
我们正在解析它们以给出树结构，然后我们要求Mechanical Turkers
rate the different phra- the different words and
评价不同的语言 - 不同的单词和
phrases on a sentiment scale of very positive to very negative.
情绪量表上的短语非常积极到非常消极。
So lots of stuff is white because it's just not sentiment-laden, right?
所以很多东西都是白色的，因为它不是充满感情的，对吧？
There's words that are the,
有的话是，
and there's phrases like the movie and
还有像电影和电影这样的短语
the movie was- which don't really have any sentiment,
电影是 - 真的没有任何情绪，
but then you have pieces that are sort of very positives pieces of
但是你会得到一些非常积极的作品
tree and negative pieces of tree that are then shown in the blue and the red.
树和负片树，然后以蓝色和红色显示。
And- so typically in sentiment datasets,
通常在情绪数据集中，
people have only labeled the entire sentence to say,
人们只用标记整句话来说，
"This is a positive sentence or a very positive sentence.
“这是一个积极的判决或非常积极的判决。
This is a negative sentence or a very negative sentence."
这是一个否定句或一个非常消极的句子。“
Crucially, what we were doing differently here is every phrase in the sentence
至关重要的是，我们在这里做的不同的是句子中的每个短语
according to our tree structure was being given a label for its positivity or negativity.
根据我们的树形结构，它被赋予了积极性或消极性的标签。
Um, and perhaps not surprisingly,
嗯，也许并不奇怪，
just the fact that you have a lot more annotations like that, um,
事实上，你有更多这样的注释，嗯，
just improves the behavior of classifiers because you kind of can
只是改善了分类器的行为，因为你可以
do better attribution of which words in a sentence are positive or negative. Um.
更好地归因于句子中的哪些词是积极的还是消极的。嗯。
So, these were um were results of sort of preceding models.
所以，这些都是前面模型的结果。
So the green is a Naive Bayes model except it not only uses individual words,
所以绿色是朴素贝叶斯模型，除了它不仅使用单个词，
but it uses pairs of words.
但它使用成对的单词。
It turns out if you're building a traditional classifier and you
事实证明，如果你正在构建一个传统的分类器和你
wanna do sentiment analysis as opposed to something like topic classification,
想做情绪分析，而不是像主题分类那样
you get a lot better results if you also use word pair features.
如果你还使用单词对功能，你会得到更好的结果。
And that's because it does a baby bit of um composition for you.
那是因为它为你做了一点点的成分。
You don't only have features for not an interesting,
你不仅有一个有趣的功能，
but you can have a feature for not
但你可以有一个功能
interesting and that lets you model a certain amount of stuff.
有趣，这可以让你模拟一定数量的东西。
Um, and then these are our older generations of neural networks,
嗯，然后这些是我们老一代的神经网络，
our ori- original tree structured neural network and our matrix vector one.
我们的原始树结构神经网络和我们的矩阵向量一。
And so simply having- for these sort of fixed models,
因此，对于这些固定模型，
simply having the richer supervision that comes from our new treebank,
只是拥有来自我们新的树库的更丰富的监督，
it's sort of moved up the performance of every model.
它提升了每个模型的性能。
So even um, for just the um,
所以，即使是嗯，对于嗯，
Naive Bayes model's performances going up about four percent um,
朴素贝叶斯模型的表现上涨约4％，
because of the fact um,
因为这个事实，
that it now knows more about which
它现在知道更多关于哪个
particular words are positive or negative in the sentences.
句子中的特定词语是正面的或负面的。
Um, but still none of these performances are really great.
嗯，但这些表演中没有一个真的很棒。
Um, so we still thought that well can we build better models of how to do this.
嗯，所以我们仍然认为我们可以建立更好的模型来解决这个问题。
Um, in particular, if you look at sentences with
嗯，特别是，如果你看看句子
sort of various kinds of negation you know,
你知道各种各样的否定，
things like should've been funnier,
这样的事情本来应该更有趣，
these models in general still couldn't capture the right meanings for them.
一般来说，这些模型仍然无法捕捉到它们的正确含义。
And so that led into our fourth model of how to do this,
因此，这导致了我们的第四个如何做到这一点的模型，
which is this idea of recursive neural tensor networks.
这就是递归神经张量网络的概念。
Um, and so what we wanted to be able to do is go back to just having um,
嗯，所以我们想要做的就是回到刚刚，
meanings of words be vectors,
单词的意义是向量，
but nevertheless despite that to be able to
但尽管如此，尽管如此
have a meaningful phrase where the two vectors um,
有两个向量的有意义的短语，
acted on each other.
相互作用。
And well, you know, this kind of,
嗯，你知道，这种，
this is the picture of what we did when we were
这是我们做的时候所做的事情
doing attention in a bi-linear way, right?
以双线方式注意，对吧？
We had vectors for two words.
我们有两个单词的向量。
We stuck a matrix in between and we used
我们在中间插入了一个矩阵，我们使用了
that and gave an attention and got an attention score out.
那引起了注意并得到了一个注意力得分。
So that let these two vectors interact with each other,
那么让这两个向量相互作用，
but it only produced one number as the output.
但它只产生一个数字作为输出。
But there's a way to fix that,
但是有办法解决这个问题，
which is to say well rather than having a matrix here,
这也就是说，而不是在这里有一个矩阵，
what we could stick here is a three-dimensional cube,
我们在这里可以坚持的是一个三维立方体，
which physicists and deep learning people now call a tensor, right?
物理学家和深度学习者现在称之为张量，对吧？
So a tensor is just higher multi-dimensional array um,
所以张量只是更高的多维数组，
in computer science terms.
用计算机科学术语。
Um, so if we sort of made that a tensor,
嗯，所以如果我们做出那种张量，
you know, it's like we have sort of multiple layers of matrix here.
你知道，这就像我们在这里有多层矩阵。
And so the end result of that is we get one number here and one number here.
因此，最终结果是我们在这里得到一个数字，在这里得到一个数字。
So in total, we get out a size two vector,
总的来说，我们得到了一个二号矢量，
which is all we need in my baby example where
这就是我在宝宝示例中所需要的全部内容
baby examples, where we only have these two component vectors for words.
宝贝示例，其中我们只有这两个单词向量的单词。
But in general, we have a tensor with
但总的来说，我们有一个张量
the extra mention dimension of the size of our word vector.
我们的单词向量大小的额外提及维度。
And so therefore, we will get a word vector, w hat,
因此，我们将得到一个单词向量，w，
we will get a phrase vector out from the composition that's the same size of
我们将从相同大小的组合中获取一个短语向量
the input vectors and will allow them to
输入向量并允许它们
interact with each other in working out the meaning of the entire thing.
在计算整个事物的意义时彼此互动。
Okay. Um, all right.
好的。嗯，好的。
So at that point um,
嗯，那个时候，
we use the resulting vectors um um,
我们使用生成的向量um，
so we had our neural tensor network.
所以我们有了神经张量网络。
We actually combined it together with the sort of previous kind of layer we used to have,
我们实际上将它与我们以前的那种层结合在一起，
our sort of first RNN, maybe you  didn't need to do this,
我们的第一个RNN，也许你不需要这样做，
but we just decided to add that in as well,
但我们只是决定添加它，
put things through a nonlinearity and that was then
把事情放在一个非线性的时候
giving us our new representation of phrases.
给我们新的短语表示。
We built that up the tree and then at the end,
我们把它建在树上，然后在最后，
we could classify the meaning of any phrase um,
我们可以对任何短语的含义进行分类，
in the same kind of way with softmax regression and we could
以softmax回归的方式，我们可以
train these weights with gradient descent to predict sentiment.
用梯度下降训练这些权重来预测情绪。
And so this actually worked pretty nicely.
所以这实际上非常好用。
I mean in particular,
我的意思是，
it didn't so really work any better with just the sentence labels.
只用句子标签就没那么好了。
But if we train the model with our treebank,
但是如果我们用树库训练模型，
we could then get a kind of- of whatever
然后我们可以得到一种什么
that is about another couple of percent in performance,
这是另外几个百分点的表现，
and so that seemed good.
这似乎很好。
And so in particular,
特别是，
it seemed to do a much better job of actually understanding meaning composition.
它似乎在实际理解意义构成方面做得更好。
So here's the kind of sentence where you have there are slow and repetitive parts,
所以这里有一种句子，你有缓慢和重复的部分，
but it has just enough spice to keep it interesting.
但它有足够的香料来保持它的趣味性。
And the model seen here is pretty good at understanding.
这里看到的模型非常善于理解。
Okay, this part of the sentence is negative,
好的，这部分句子是否定的，
this part of the sentence is positive,
这部分句子是积极的，
and actually when you stick the two halves together,
实际上当你把两半粘在一起时，
the end result is a sentence that's positive in meaning.
最终的结果是一个意义上积极的句子。
But focusing in a little bit more what seems
但是更多地关注似乎更多
like it's especially good was for the first time this actually
喜欢它特别好，这实际上是第一次
did seem like it could do a better job of
看起来好像可以做得更好
working out sort of what happens when you do things like negation.
找出当你做出否定之类的事情时会发生什么。
So here we have it's just incredibly dull and it's definitely not dull.
所以在这里，我们有它非常沉闷，它绝对不会沉闷。
So if it's definitely not dull,
所以，如果它绝对不是沉闷的，
that's actually means it's good, right?
这实际上意味着它很好，对吗？
Can we work out the meaning of, it's definitely not dull?
我们可以弄清楚它的含义吗，它绝对不会沉闷？
And so um, these, this is sort of
所以，嗯，这些，这是一种
showing sort of what happens when you have a negative,
显示当你有负面时会发生什么，
a negative sentence that's further negated.
一个被否定的否定句。
So if you go from um,
所以，如果你从嗯，
so if you sort of do
所以如果你这样做的话
a annex- negation of a negative thing should become moderately positive, right?
附件 - 否定的东西应该变得适度积极，对吧？
So that if you have dull is negative and if you say not dull,
所以，如果你有沉闷是消极的，如果你说不沉闷，
it doesn't mean it's fantastic,
这并不意味着它太棒了，
but it means it's moderately positive.
但这意味着它适度积极。
And so for either a kind of Naive Bayes model or our preceding models,
对于一种朴素贝叶斯模型或我们之前的模型，
they weren't capable of capturing that of sort of going from dull to not dull your,
他们无法捕捉从沉闷到不沉闷的那种，
your meaning computation did not come out any more positive.
你的意思计算没有出来更积极。
Whereas this sort of neural tensor network was
而这种神经张量网络是
capturing the fact that not dull meant that it was reasonably good.
捕捉到不沉闷的事实意味着它相当不错。
So that was progress. Um, yes.
这就是进步。嗯，是的。
So I think that's as much as I'll um show you really now about applying
所以我认为这就像我现在向你展示的那样
these tree structured neural networks um, to natural language.
这些树结构的神经网络，对于自然语言。
Um, you know, I think the summary I sort of said at the beginning um is that I
嗯，你知道，我认为我在开头说的总结就是我
think you know, they're kind of interesting ideas and linguistic connections here.
你知道，他们在这里有一些有趣的想法和语言联系。
I mean, for various reasons,
我的意思是，出于各种原因，
these ideas haven't been um,
这些想法不是嗯，
pursued a ton in recent years of natural language processing.
近年来追求自然语言处理。
You know, one is in all honesty people have found that um,
你知道，一个人是诚实的，人们已经找到了，嗯，
once you have high dimensional vectors
一旦你有高维矢量
in things like the kind of sequence models that we've looked at,
在我们看过的那种序列模型之类的东西中，
whether it's meaning things like the sort of LSTM models or any of
是否意味着像LSTM模型或任何类型的东西
the more recent contextual language models, those work incredibly well um,
最新的语境语言模型，那些工作非常好，嗯，
and it's not, it's not clear that overall these models work better.
而事实并非如此，目前尚不清楚整体这些模型的效果是否更好。
The second reason is sort of a computational reason,
第二个原因是计算原因，
which is um, GPUs work great when you're doing uniform computation.
这是嗯，当你进行统一计算时，GPU工作得很好。
And the beauty of having something like a sequence model is that there's uh,
拥有像序列模型这样的东西的美妙之处在于，呃，
there's just one determinant computation you are doing
你正在做的只有一个决定性计算
along the sequence or in the convolutional neural network,
沿序列或卷积神经网络，
there's one determinant um,
有一个决定因素，
computation you're doing up um,
计算你在做什么，
through your convolutional layers and therefore,
通过你的卷积层因此，
things can be represented and computed efficiently on a GPU.
事物可以在GPU上有效地表示和计算。
The huge problem with these kind of models was what computations you are
这些模型的巨大问题是你的计算
going to do depended on which structure you are assigning to the sentence,
要做什么取决于你分配给句子的结构，
and every sentence was going to have a different structure, and so therefore,
每个句子都会有不同的结构，因此，
there was no way to batch the computations over a group of
没有办法批量计算一组
sentences and have the same computations being done for
句子并进行相同的计算
different sentences, it sort of undermined the ability
不同的句子，它有点破坏了这种能力
to sort of efficiently build these models in the large.
在大型中有效地构建这些模型。
The thing I thought I'd just sort of say a moment about at the end.
我认为我最后会说一下这个问题。
Um, the funny thing is that although these haven't been used much for,
嗯，有趣的是，尽管这些还没有被广泛使用，
um, language in the last few years, um,
嗯，最近几年的语言，嗯，
that they've actually had some use and found different applications in different places,
他们实际上有一些用处并在不同的地方找到了不同的应用，
um, which is just sort of seen kind of cute.
嗯，这有点可爱。
Um, so this is actually an application from physics.
嗯，所以这实际上是物理学的应用。
Um, and I think I'm going to just have to read this and
嗯，我想我只需要阅读这篇文章
so I have no idea what half the words mean.
所以我不知道一半的意思是什么。
Um, but, um, what it says is by far the most common structures seen in collisions at
嗯，但是，嗯，它说的是到目前为止碰撞中看到的最常见的结构
the Large Hadron Collider are collimated sprays of energetic hadrons referred to as jets.
大型强子对撞机是被称为喷气式飞机的精力充沛的强子喷射。
These jets are produced from the fragmentation and hadronization of
这些喷气机是由碎裂和强化产生的
quarks and gluons as described by quantum chromodynamics.
量子色动力学描述的夸克和胶子。
Anyone knows what that means?
谁知道这意味着什么？
Um, I hope you're following along here.
嗯，我希望你跟着来这里。
Um, one compelling physics challenge is to search for
嗯，一个令人信服的物理挑战是搜索
highly boosted standard model particles decaying hadronically.
高度增强的标准模型颗粒长期腐烂。
Unfortunately there's a large background from jets produced by more mundane,
不幸的是，有更多平凡的喷气式飞机有很大的背景，
um, QCD, that's quantum chromodynamics processes.
嗯，QCD，这是量子色动力学过程。
In this work, we propose instead a solution for
在这项工作中，我们提出了一个解决方案
jet classification based on an analogy between
喷射分类基于类比之间的类比
quantum chromodynamics and natural languages as inspired by
量子色动力学和自然语言的启发
several works from natural language, um, processing.
从自然语言，嗯，处理的几个作品。
Much like a sentence is composed of words
就像句子由单词组成一样
following a syntactic structure organized as a parse tree,
遵循组织为解析树的句法结构，
a jet is also composed of 4-momenta following a structure dictated by
喷射器也由4-momenta组成，遵循由结构决定的结构
QCD and organized via
QCD和组织通过
the clustering history of a sequential co- combination jet algorithm.
序贯联合喷射算法的聚类历史。
Um, so anyway um, yeah with these jets you see they're getting
嗯，无论如何，是的，是的，你会看到他们正在使用这些喷气式飞机
a tree structure over them and they're using the tree recursive neural network,
它们上面的树结构，它们使用树递归神经网络，
um, to model it.
嗯，模仿它。
Um, well that's a little bit far afield but to show you just one more example, um,
嗯，那有点远，但是再向你展示一个例子，嗯，
that another place where these models have actually being quite
另一个地方，这些模型实际上是相当的
useful is for doing things in programming languages.
有用的是用编程语言做事。
And I think in part this,
我认为在某种程度上，
this is because the application is easier in programming languages.
这是因为应用程序在编程语言中更容易。
So unlike in natural language where we have this uncertainty as to what is
因此，与自然语言不同，我们对这是什么有不确定性
the correct parse tree because there's a lot of ambiguity in natural language,
正确的解析树因为自然语言存在很多歧义，
in programming languages, um,
在编程语言中，嗯，
the parse trees are actually pretty determinant.
解析树实际上是非常重要的。
Um, so a group of people at Berkeley, Dawn Song and her students have worked on doing
嗯，伯克利的一群人，Dawn Song和她的学生们都在努力
programming language translation by building
通过构建编程语言翻译
tree recursive neural network encoder-decoders.
树递归神经网络编码器 - 解码器。
So that you're building up a tree structured
这样你就可以建立一个结构化的树
neural network representation of a program in one language.
一种语言的程序的神经网络表示。
This is a CoffeeScript program and then you're wanting to build a tree to
这是一个CoffeeScript程序，然后你想要构建一个树
tree model which is then translating that to a program in a different language.
树模型，然后将其转换为不同语言的程序。
And they've been able to do that and get good results.
他们已经能够做到这一点，并取得了良好的效果。
Um, I was too lazy to retype this table.
嗯，我懒得重新输入这张桌子。
So this is probably a bit,
所以这可能有点，
bit hard to read.
有点难读。
But what's it's contrasting is for a number of programs this is the sort of
但对比的是，对于许多程序来说，这就是那种情况
CoffeeScript to JavaScript, um, um, translation.
CoffeeScript到JavaScript，嗯，嗯，翻译。
They're comparing using tree to tree models.
他们使用树与树模型进行比较。
Um, and then using sequence to sequence
嗯，然后使用序列来排序
models and then they tried both other combinations,
模型，然后他们尝试了其他组合，
sequence to tree and tree to sequence.
序列到树和树到序列。
Um, and what they find is you can get the best
嗯，他们发现你可以得到最好的
results with the tree to tree neural network models.
结果用树到树的神经网络模型。
And in particular these tree to tree models are
特别是这些树到树的模型
augmented with attention so they have attention like we talked about
注意力增强，所以他们像我们谈到的那样受到关注
the sequence to sequence models where you're then being able to do attention back to
顺序模型的序列，然后你可以回到那里
nodes in the tree structure which is a pretty natural way of doing translation.
树结构中的节点是一种非常自然的翻译方式。
And indeed what these results show is if you don't have- that's right these results
事实上，这些结果表明，如果你没有 - 这些结果是正确的
show is if you don't have the attention operation it doesn't work at all.
show是如果你没有注意操作它根本不起作用。
It's too difficult, um,
这太难了，嗯，
to get things, um,
得到的东西，嗯，
sort of done if you've just sort of trying to create
如果你只想尝试创造，那就完成了
a single tree representation and then say generate the tra- the translation from that.
单个树表示，然后说从那里生成tra-翻译。
But if you can do it with this sort of putting attention
但如果你能用这种注意力来做到这一点
into the different modes, um, that's great.
进入不同的模式，嗯，这很棒。
Um, you might- If you know what CoffeeScript is you might, um,
嗯，你可能 - 如果你知道CoffeeScript是什么，嗯，
feel like wait that's cheating slightly because
感觉好像等待那个作弊，因为
CoffeeScript is a bit too similar to JavaScript.
CoffeeScript与JavaScript有点相似。
Um, but they've also, um,
嗯，但他们也是，嗯，
done it in other languages.
用其他语言完成。
So this is going between Java and C# and this is a sort of
所以这是在Java和C＃之间进行的，这是一种
handwritten Java to C# converter that you can
你可以手写Java到C＃转换器
download from GitHub if you want but it doesn't actually work that well.
如果你愿意，可以从GitHub下载，但它实际上并没有那么好用。
Um, and they're able to show,
嗯，他们能够表现出来，
the- they're able to build a far better, um,
他们能够建立一个更好的，嗯，
Java to C# translator,
Java到C＃翻译器，
um, doing that.
嗯，这样做。
Um, so that's actually kind of cool.
嗯，所以这真的很酷。
And it's good to know that tree structured recursive neural networks
知道树结构的递归神经网络是很好的
are good for some things.
对某些事情有好处。
Um, so I'm pleased to see work like this.
嗯，所以我很高兴看到这样的工作。
Okay. I'm, I'm, just about done but I thought,
好的。我，我，刚刚完成，但我想，
um, before, um, finishing,
嗯，之前，嗯，完成，
I'd just mention one other [NOISE] thing which is sort of nothing to do
我只提到另一个[NOISE]的事情，这是无关紧要的事情
with natural language processing precisely but it's about AI.
精确的自然语言处理，但它是关于AI。
Um, but I wanted to sort of put in a little bit of advertisement.
嗯，但我想要做一些广告。
Um, that's something that a number of us have been
嗯，这是我们很多人的事
working on very hard for the last year or so,
在过去一年左右的时间里努力工作，
is developing, um, a new Stanford Institute for Human-Centered Artificial Intelligence.
正在开发一个新的斯坦福人类中心人工智能研究所。
And actually the launch of this institute is going to be on Monday of exam week,
实际上这个研究所的发布将在周一的考试周，
just when you're maximally concentrating on things such as this.
就在你最大限度地专注于这样的事情的时候。
Um, but our hope is that we can have a lot of
嗯，但我们希望我们可以有很多
new activity around artificial intelligence,
围绕人工智能的新活动，
taking a much broader perspective to artificial intelligence, um,
对人工智能采取更广泛的视角，嗯，
which is centrally viewing it from the viewpoint of humans and working out, um,
从人类的角度集中观察它，锻炼，嗯，
I'll- exploring a much broader range of issues that
我将探讨更广泛的问题
embrace a lot of the interests of the rest of the university whether
拥抱大学其他部分的很多利益
it's the social sciences and humanities, or also variously
它是社会科学和人文科学，或者也是各种各样的
in professional schools like the law school and the business school.
在法学院和商学院等专业学校。
Um, so let's just quickly say a minute about that.
嗯，让我们快点说一下。
Um, that the, the sort of motivating idea is that sort of for most of my life sort
嗯，那种激励的想法就是我生命中的大部分时间
of AI seemed like a kind of
人工智能似乎是一种
a fun intellectual quest as
一个有趣的知识分子追求
to whether you could write bits of software that did anything,
你是否可以写一些做任何事情的软件，
um, halfway intelligent but that's clearly not what's going to be,
嗯，中途聪明，但显然不会是什么，
what's happening for the next 25 years.
未来25年发生了什么。
That we're now at this point in which
我们现在正处于这一点
artificial intelligence systems are being unleashed on society.
人工智能系统正在社会中释放出来。
Um, and well hopefully they do some good things but as we've
嗯，希望他们做一些好事，但正如我们所做的那样
increasingly been seeing there are lots of
越来越多地看到有很多
also lots of opportunities for them to do bad things.
也有很多机会让他们做坏事。
And even if we're not imagining Terminator scenarios,
即使我们没有想象终结者场景，
there are just lots of places where people are using
人们正在使用很多地方
machine learning and AI algorithms for making decisions.
用于制定决策的机器学习和AI算法。
Some of the worst ones are things like sentencing guidelines in
其中一些最糟糕的事情就像量刑指南
courts where you have very biased algorithms making bad decisions and
法院，你有非常偏见的算法做出错误的决定和
people are starting to become a lot more aware of the issues and so
人们开始变得更加意识到这些问题
effectively we are wanting to have this institute sort of
实际上我们想要这个机构
embracing a lot of the work of social scientists,
拥抱社会科学家的许多工作，
the ethicists and other people to actually explore how to have an AI
伦理学家和其他人实际探索如何拥有AI
that's really improving human lives rather than having the opposite effect.
这确实改善了人的生活，而不是产生相反的效果。
And so the three themes,
所以这三个主题，
um, that we're, um,
嗯，我们是，嗯，
mainly emphasizing for this institute is the first one in the top left is
这个研究所主要强调的是左上角的第一个
developing AI technologies but we're particularly
开发人工智能技术，但我们尤其如此
interested in making linkages back to human intelligence.
有兴趣将人际关系联系起来。
So cognitive science and neuroscience
认知科学和神经科学
that when a lot of the early formative work in AI was
当人工智能的许多早期形成工作时
done including all of
完成包括所有
the early work in neural networks like the development of back propagation,
神经网络的早期工作，如反向传播的发展，
it was actually largely done in the context of cognitive science.
它实际上主要是在认知科学的背景下完成的。
Right? And that was sort of a linkage that tended to get lost in
对？这种联系往往会迷失方向
the '90s and 2000s statistical machine learning emphasis.
'90年代和2000年代统计机器学习的重点。
And I think it would be good to renew that.
而且我认为更新它会更好。
Um, the top right, um,
嗯，右上角，嗯，
there's paying much more attention to
有更多的关注
the human and societal impact of AI and so this is looking at legal issues,
人工智能对人类和社会的影响，所以这是关注法律问题，
economic issues, labor forces,
经济问题，劳动力，
ethics, um, green power, politics, whatever you are.
道德，嗯，绿色权力，政治，无论你是什么。
But then down at the bottom is something where it seems like
但是接下来就是它看起来像的东西
there's just kind of enormous opportunities to do more which is,
有更多的机会去做更多的事情，
um, how can we build technology that actually augments human lives.
嗯，我们怎样才能建立真正增强人类生活的技术。
Like to some extent here tech- we've got technology with AI augmenting human lives.
在某种程度上，这里技术 - 我们已经获得了人工智能增强人类生活的技术。
So all of your cell phones have speech recognition in them now.
所以你的所有手机现在都有语音识别功能。
So you know that's AI, um,
所以你知道那是AI，嗯，
that can augment, um, your human lives.
这可以增加你的人生。
But there's a sense of which not very much of
但是有一种感觉不是很多
artificial intelligence has actually been put into the service of augmenting human lives.
人工智能实际上已经被用于增强人类生活。
Like most of what a cell phone has on it is still
就像手机上的大部分内容一样
sort of clever and cute stuff done by
完成的一些聪明和可爱的东西
HCI people and designers which is very nice a lot of
HCI的人和设计师非常好
the time when you're using your map program or something but we don't really have
您使用地图程序或其他东西的时间，但我们没有
much AI inside these devices helping to make people's lives better.
这些设备中的人工智能有助于改善人们的生活。
And so we're hoping not only for individuals when applications like health care,
所以我们不仅希望个人在医疗保健，
um, to be doing much more of sort of putting
嗯，要做更多的推杆
artificial intelligence into human-centered applications.
人工智能融入以人为本的应用。
Um, anyway that's my brief advertisement.
嗯，无论如何这是我的简短广告。
Um, look it out for this while you're not studying for your exams.
嗯，在你不参加考试的时候看看这个。
And I think there'll be sort of lots of opportunities, um,
而且我认为会有很多机会，嗯，
for students and others to be getting more involved in this in the coming months.
学生和其他人将在未来几个月内更多地参与其中。
Okay. Thank you very much.
好的。非常感谢你。
Um, and I will see you later, um, at the poster session.
嗯，我稍后会见到你，嗯，在海报会议上。
[APPLAUSE].
[掌声]。